<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 2018-resolutions | sudo random]]></title>
  <link href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/categories/2018-resolutions/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/"/>
  <updated>2018-01-31T21:29:58+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://rajatkhanduja.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Rajat Khanduja]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2017 in review and the year ahead]]></title>
    <link href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2018/01/28/back-from-the-dead/"/>
    <updated>2018-01-28T12:18:05+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2018/01/28/back-from-the-dead</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Perhaps a better title for this post would be “Back from the dead”! It has been
so long that I got lost in my own blog setup. So lost, that I couldn’t help but
wonder if it was really a good idea to <a href="/techblog/2014/03/10/migrating-to-octopress/">use Octopress in the first place</a>. 
Finally, I got around to writing this post, but not without having to check the
<a href="http://octopress.org/docs/blogging/">Octopress
documentation</a>! </p>

<p>Anyway, now that I am back here, I intend to write more often. In fact, that’s
one of my new year resolutions! But I am getting ahead of myself. Before I go on to
commit to some goals for this year (as I should have done soon after reading
<a href="http://www.nickwinter.net/the-motivation-hacker">The Motivation Hacker</a> in
2014), I’d like to review the last year. Before any one blames me of
‘plagiarism’, I’d like to give credit, where credit is due. This format  is
highly inspired by some other similar <a href="https://vickychijwani.me/2016-year-in-review/">review
posts</a> I have <a href="https://vickychijwani.me/2014-year-in-review/">come
across</a> <a href="https://prakhar.me/articles/2014-year-in-review/">over the
years</a></p>

<!--more-->

<h2 id="what-all-happened">2017 : What all happened!</h2>
<p>The year was a peculiar, to say the least. I failed terribly on all my goals
(except one). Here are the goals (however vauge) and what I achieved :-</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Read 15 books</strong> (The only goal I managed to achieve)</p>

    <p>In fact, <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/user_challenges/7019921">I read 16
books</a>! (Where would I be
without Goodreads to track my progress on such goals). Looking back at that
list, I feel good about covering different kinds of books. </p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>1 project per month</strong></p>

    <p>Towards the end of 2016, I had come across the interesting idea of resolving
to ship <a href="https://blog.1ppm.club/12-months-12-side-projects-are-you-in-c395dbcd648e">1 project every month for the entire
year</a>.
Although I didn’t end up joining the club, or fully committed to the idea, I
had hoped to make good progress keeping that average in mind. I failed
miserably.  Although I started well on 
<a href="https://github.com/rajatkhanduja/pigit">Pigit</a>, my interest soon fizzled
out. I guess, that’s truly the reason why you should commit to such goals
publicly. My Github commits were pretty low as well.</p>

    <p><img src="/images/github_commits_2017.png" title="“Open Source Contributions”" ></p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Run 1000 km</strong></p>

    <p>As you can see in the image below, I barely managed to achieve 40% of the goal,
~100km of which came in December! 
<img src="/images/runkeeper_2017.png" title="“2017 running summary from Runkeeper”" ></p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>Looking at just the goals, it would appear that 2017 turned out to be quite an
unproductive year. However, it was not all that bad. Yes, I failed to do a lot
of the things I had expected to do, but that was also because things drastically
changed over the year. </p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p><a href="http://www.thehindu.com/business/Industry/myntra-acquires-inlogg/article18143405.ece">InLogg got acquired by Myntra!</a></p>

    <p>Towards the end of 2015, I had joined Preeti, Prateek and Hemant to build and 
grow InLogg! Early 2017, Myntra acquired InLogg and I joined them.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Later in the year, however, I moved to London to work as a Software Engineer
at Facebook! </p>
  </li>
</ol>

<h2 id="goals-for-2018">Goals for 2018</h2>

<p>Having quickly glossed over the missed goals last year, it’s time to establish (and 
start working on) the goals for 2018.  Unlike previous years, this would act 
as the public declaration that I couldn’t later deny (for anyone in doubt,
you could track this history of this file on Github)</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Run 1000 km</strong> (100)</p>

    <p>Yeah, that’s me taking a second shot at the goal. This time, I am more optimistic, however.
I have already signed up for the <a href="https://www.edinburghmarathon.com/events/half-marathon/">Edinburgh Half
Marathon</a> in May</p>

    <p>You can track my progress on <a href="https://connect.garmin.com/modern/profile/eea59256-a5cd-4d40-aa0c-72577a0c9308">Garmin
Connect</a>
I use my <a href="https://buy.garmin.com/en-GB/GB/p/538374">Garmin VivoActive HR</a>
(since Jun’17) to log my runs. However, I also sync my runs to
<a href="https://www.strava.com/athletes/6961634">Strava</a> and
<a href="https://runkeeper.com/user/rajatkhanduja/profile?goalId=azziv&amp;">Runkeeper</a>
using <a href="http://tapiriik.com/">Tapiriik</a></p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Read 20 books</strong> (50)</p>

    <p>Thanks to Goodreads, I have gotten into the habit of setting a reading goal
every year since 2013 - how many times I have achieved it is another matter.
<a href="https://www.goodreads.com/challenges/7501-2018-reading-challenge">Goal on Goodreads</a></p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Write at least one blog post every month</strong> (20)</p>

    <p>This post is the first in that series (and now you know why a post about new
year resolutions comes towards the end of January).</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>To make my commitment to these goals even stronger, I have decided to make it 
hurt if I fail to achieve any one of these (another lesson from The Motivation
Hacker).  In the spirit of that, I commit to
donate to charity the amount mentioned in parenthesis after every goal
(totalling to 170), in GBP,
in case I fail to achieve it.</p>

<p>Cheers to an exciting new year ahead!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
