<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[sudo random]]></title>
  <link href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-06-26T12:33:50+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://rajatkhanduja.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Rajat Khanduja]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tech News: Google IO Keynote]]></title>
    <link href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/26/tech-news-google-io-keynote/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-26T02:02:17+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/26/tech-news-google-io-keynote</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ol>
  <li><a href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/26/tech-news-google-io-keynote/#android-one">Google Introduces Android One Program To Bring More Smartphones To Developing Markets</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/26/tech-news-google-io-keynote/#material-design">Google Unveils New Cross Platform Design Language “Material Design”</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/26/tech-news-google-io-keynote/#login">Google Makes Phone Logins Easier With Personal Login Feature For Android L</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/26/tech-news-google-io-keynote/#android-wear">Android Wear Smartwatches and SDK</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/26/tech-news-google-io-keynote/#android-tv">Google Introduces Android TV, Its New Platform For Smart TV Apps And Navigation</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/26/tech-news-google-io-keynote/#android-auto">Google Announces Android Auto, Promises Enabled Cars By The End Of 2014</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/26/tech-news-google-io-keynote/#deep-link">Google Blurs The Line Between Web And Native Apps On Android</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/26/tech-news-google-io-keynote/#android-app-chrome">Google will soon bring Android apps to Chrome OS</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/26/tech-news-google-io-keynote/#chromecast">Chromecast Update Introduces An AirPlay-Like Android Mirroring Feature, Photo Backdrops And More</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/26/tech-news-google-io-keynote/#cloud-updates">Updates to Google Cloud Platform: Data Flow, Cloud monitoring and Cloud Save</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/26/tech-news-google-io-keynote/#google-fit">Google Fit</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/26/tech-news-google-io-keynote/#cardboard">Giveaways at Google IO and #Cardboard!</a></li>
</ol>

<!--more-->

<p> 
 </p>

<hr />

<ol>
  <li><a name="android-one"></a><strong><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/25/android-one/">Google Introduces Android One Program To Bring More Smartphones To Developing Markets</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>
        <p>After sharing that Google now has <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/25/google-now-has-1b-active-android-users/">1 billion 30-day active
users</a>
Sundar Pichai announced the Android One program which would help increase
the number significantly.</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>This initiative will target OEMs, specifically in emerging markets, to make
smartphones more affordable to develop and release.</p>

        <blockquote><p>With Android One, Google is hoping to reduce the cost of smartphone development by identifying the components that go into a smartphone and to pre-qualify suppliers for those parts to ensure they work together.</p><p>      On the software side, Google is giving hardware manufacturers access to its Play Store to help them add locally relevant apps to their devices. It’s also handling all the software updates automatically, just like it does for Nexus devices.</p></blockquote>
      </li>
      <li>Three OEMs to start with : Cromax, Karbonn and Spice.</li>
      <li>Google is also trying to work with wireless providers to provide low cost
wireless plans.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="material-design"></a><strong><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/25/google-unveils-new-cross-platform-design-language-material-design/">Google Unveils New Cross Platform Design Language “Material Design”</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>As a part of the forthcoming, Android ‘L’ release of the Android OS, Google
announced a new universal design language, “Material Design”.
        <blockquote><p>“We imagined… what if pixels didn’t just have color, but also depth? What if there was a material that could change its texture? This lead us to something we call ‘material design,” says Matias Durate, Director of Android operating system User Experience at Google&#8230;</p></blockquote>
      </li>
      <li>The new framework is now <a href="http://www.google.com/design/">publicly available</a>.</li>
      <li>They aim is to put the framework out in the public to help create a consistent
user-experience for the different Android apps, much like Apple’s guidelines
for Mac and iOS developers.</li>
      <li>Redesigned versions of their flagship products like GMail and Calendar will
soon be introduced (for both Android and web)
        <blockquote><p>Google describes the new design as being “inspired by the study of paper and ink, yet technologically advanced and open to imagination and magic.”</p><p>      The design uses familiar tactile means of interacting with its many parts, with visual cues that are grounded in reality, Google says. Its elements also recall print-based design typography, with “deliberate color choices, edge-to-edge imagery, large-scale typography, and intentional white space create a bold and graphic interface that immerses the user in the experience.”</p><p>      Motion is another key element of the design, but is meant to be. “Motion is meaningful and appropriate, serving to focus attention and maintain continuity,” Google adds.</p></blockquote>
      </li>
      <li>Such a design centric update to Android was <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/19/a-sneak-peek-into-androids-future/">expected</a>
and several websites reported the internal project <a href="http://www.androidpolice.com/2014/06/11/exclusive-quantum-paper-and-googles-upcoming-effort-to-make-consistent-ui-simple/">‘Quantum’</a></li>
      <li>This move seems to show Google’s increased focus on user-experience and design, 
which seems to have been a distinguishing factor between iOS and Android devices.</li>
    </ul>

    <iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/Q8TXgCzxEnw" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
  </li>
  <li><a name="login"></a><strong><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/25/google-makes-phone-logins-easier-with-personal-login-feature-for-android-l/">Google Makes Phone Logins Easier With Personal Login Feature For Android ‘L’</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>Google demoed a feature that allows the user to skip logging into the phone
as the phone deduces if it is in a trusted environment.</li>
      <li>The phone looks for <em>your</em> smartphone or your Wifi network; if found, it 
doesn’t require you to authenticate yourself through a PIN or pattern.</li>
      <li>In case it senses an unknown/untrusted environment, the PIN/pattern based
login is used. </li>
      <li>This seems to be aimed at competing with Apple’s built-in fingerprint scanner.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="android-wear"></a><strong><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/25/google-launches-full-android-wear-sdk-lets-developers-create-custom-uis-and-access-sensors/">Android Wear Smartwatches and SDK</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>
        <p>After announcing that <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/25/the-first-android-wear-smartwatches-will-go-on-sale-today/">LG’s and Samsung’s first Android Wear Smartphone
watches will go on sale
immediately</a>,
Google announced that it will be releasing <a href="http://developer.android.com/wear/index.html">Android Wear SDK for
developers</a> to build upon.</p>

        <blockquote><p>&#8230; Google demoed several Android Wear functions that will be available on all Android Wear devices including swiping to dismiss messages and displaying contextual information relevant to the wearer.</p></blockquote>

        <iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/0xQ3y902DEQ" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
      </li>
      <li>On stage, there was also an interesting demo of how the smartwatch showed
contextually relevant information. 
        <ul>
          <li>The wearer had a flight ticket for that day, which was displayed on the watch, like a Google Now card. </li>
          <li>One could see more information by tapping on it.</li>
          <li>An incoming message (on the phone) notification was shown on the watch and swiping it 
away also removed the notification from the phone.</li>
          <li>It was also able to give directions to a place and log/display the number
of steps taken by the wearer.</li>
          <li>Also, it was able to respond to voice commands like searching, responding
to a message and setting an alarm.</li>
        </ul>

        <iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/s_LYIQwwQVQ" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>The SDK allows developers to create custom UI, allowing their apps to 
leverage the sensors, taps and voice commands on the smartwatches.</p>

        <blockquote><p>The company demoed an app from Eat24, for example, which would allow you to order a pizza from the watch within 30 seconds and just a few taps.</p></blockquote>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>Besides LG and Samsung, they have some other partners. Moto 360 is expected
later this year. Other partners include Asus, Qualcomm, Intel and HTC.</p>
      </li>
      <li>Android Wear, for style, supports both square and round shaped watches. 
LG and Samsung’s first watches are square-shaped, while Moto360, will
be round shaped.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="android-tv"></a><strong><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/25/google-introduces-android-tv-its-new-platform-for-smart-tv-apps-and-navigation/">Google Introduces Android TV, Its New Platform For Smart TV Apps And Navigation</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>Referring to it as the ‘biggest screen in the house’, Google announced 
a new <a href="http://www.android.com/tv/">Android TV operating system</a>.</li>
      <li>It’s software (OS) that will be embedded into smart televisions by 
third party OEMs, much like the Android OS was used by smartphone
manufacturers</li>
      <li>Android TV will work with a number of chipsets and is designed to enable
developers to create apps using the same Android toolset they used for
phones and tablets.</li>
      <li>Android TV will play movies and TV shows and could be controlled by
phones, tablets and even smartwatches.</li>
      <li>Your smartphone or tablet could act as the controller for games played on
Android TV.</li>
      <li>It will have full Chromecast support, which itself received significant
updates, allowing users to beam content from their mobile devices to
their TV.</li>
      <li>This is not the first time Google is trying to enter the TV market. Earlier
attempts, including Google TV, didn’t succeed.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="android-auto"></a><strong><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/25/google-announces-android-auto-promises-enabled-cars-by-end-of-2014/">Google Announces Android Auto, Promises Enabled Cars By The End Of 2014</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>Lately, a lot of road accidents have been attributed to drivers fumbling 
with their phones. With the intention to change this and allow user to 
leverage the power of Android without losing sight of the road, Google
announced <a href="http://www.android.com/auto/">Android Auto</a></li>
      <li>Android-auto connects the user’s smartphone with the car, to provide 
context based information, navigation and notifications on a large-enough
screen on the dashboard.</li>
      <li>The user can interact with it using voice commands or keys on the steering.
While the touch based navigation still works, it’s not as bad as dealing
with the small screen of the phone.</li>
      <li>During the demo, they showed how a driver could start navigation to a 
destination through just voice commands. </li>
      <li>Integration with Google Now allows Android-auto to read your text messages 
out loud to you while you are driving and allows you to dictate and 
send a reply.</li>
      <li>25 car manufacturers have promised to build Android-Auto powered cars
and the first cars are expected to roll out by the end of this year.</li>
      <li>Android Auto SDK will be released soon.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="deep-link"></a><strong><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/25/google-blurs-the-line-between-web-and-native-apps-on-android/">Google Blurs The Line Between Web And Native Apps On Android</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>Google demoed the new version of Chrome for the next Android version (Android ‘L’).
        <blockquote><p>But it isn’t just a better version of Chrome. There is a clear and more profound message coming from Google. The company wants to blend native apps with web tabs. And the end of native apps as we know them could be closer than we might think.</p></blockquote>
      </li>
      <li>App switcher now looks like Safari on iOS, with recent apps looking like
cards in a drawer.
<img class="center" src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2014/06/img_00391.jpg?w=738" title="'New app switcher'" /></li>
      <li>Each tab in Chrome gets is shown like a separate app!</li>
      <li>
        <p>Google has already been supporting <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2013/10/31/android-4-4-kitkat-app-indexing/">deep-links to other
applications</a>
through search results. For instance, if you searched for a book on Google Now,
the search result that links to Goodreads, could actually launched the
Goodreads app, letting you leverage the interface designed by Goodreads
for mobile. They are now expanding this feature to many more apps.</p>

        <blockquote><p>Knowing all this, imagine for a second what Android L will look like. You turn on your phone, search for something in Google using voice search on your home screen. It launches Chrome. You tap on the first search result, it launches a native app. You switch apps to read this article you found earlier in Chrome.</p><p>      Back, and forth, and back, and forth between the web and native apps. After a while, you won’t even notice if you’re on the web or in a native app.</p></blockquote>
      </li>
      <li>Google is possibly doing this because it has been traditionally centered
around web with most of its revenue coming from ads. </li>
      <li>It could be possible that in the future Google tries to make Android
a very thin OS layer letting all the apps be web-based. This would be 
something like <a href="http://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/os/">Mozilla’s FirefoxOS</a> or <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WebOS">Palm’s WebOS</a></li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="android-app-chrome"></a><strong><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/25/google-will-soon-bring-android-apps-to-chrome-os/">Google will soon bring Android apps to Chrome OS</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>The Android apps will essentially run in an emulator on the Chrome OS
Desktop and will be available in the launcher.</li>
      <li>No expected time was given for this feature, however, they did demo a
few apps (eg: Evernote) to show how it would work.</li>
      <li>They also seem to be looking at a tighter integration of Chrome OS and
Android. 
        <ul>
          <li>If you come close to your Chromebook with your phone, it will 
automatically log you in, skipping the authentication step.</li>
          <li>This is quite like the smartwatch unlocking your Android phone.</li>
          <li>Also, the notifications on your Android phone would be available on 
Chromebook as desktop notifications. Currently, this is possible
to achieve using a combination of app on Android and extension on
Google Chrome. <a href="https://www.pushbullet.com/">PushBullet</a>, too,
provides this feature.</li>
        </ul>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="chromecast"></a><strong><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/25/chromecast-update-introduces-an-airplay-like-android-mirroring-feature-photo-backdrops-and-more/">Chromecast Update Introduces An AirPlay-Like Android Mirroring Feature, Photo Backdrops And More</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li><a href="http://www.google.com/intl/en/chrome/devices/chromecast/index.html">Chromecast</a>,
Google’s popular $35 dongle that plugs into your TV’s HDMI port, letting
you stream video and music to your television, received a number of
updates. </li>
      <li>
        <p>A new feature allows anyone to share the screen without the hassle of 
logging onto the same wifi network as the Chromecast enabled television.</p>

        <blockquote><p>“So how do we do that?,” asks Chandra. “We’re using a variety of technologies to confirm that you’re in the same room as the Chromecast. If for some reason we can’t automatically detect that, you can enter an on-screen PIN,” he explains.</p></blockquote>
      </li>
      <li>This would make it more convenient for some guest to share photos or 
videos on the TV.</li>
      <li>Another feature, Backdrop, lets you turn ‘the biggest screen’ in the house
into a photo frame of sorts when it is not being used otherwise.</li>
      <li>It lets you slide through your own photo albums (on Google+) or a random
set of images showing scenic landscapes, art, lifestyle, etc.</li>
      <li>
        <p>The Chromecast app on your mobile could be used to learn more about 
the images on screen (in case you like the image or want to know more
about it).</p>

        <blockquote><p>However, the standout feature in the Chromecast update is its new ability to allow any Android device to be mirrored, wirelessly, onto a TV. Google built its own framework for this, allowing it to cut down on the latency, Chandra said.<br />      During the demo, the company showed how you can switch this feature on from the settings, making everything on your phone immediately appear on the TV, including things like Google Earth and even your phone’s camera viewfinder – the latter which was aimed at the audience for a little frivolity before wrapping up the announcement.</p></blockquote>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="cloud-updates"></a><strong><a href="http://googledevelopers.blogspot.in/2014/06/cloud-platform-at-google-io-new-big.html">Updates to Google Cloud Platform: Data Flow, Cloud monitoring and Cloud Save</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>
        <p>Google announced a new addition to its <a href="https://cloud.google.com/">Cloud
Platform</a>, Data
Flow</p>

        <blockquote><p>Cloud Dataflow is a fully managed service for creating data pipelines that ingest, transform and analyze data in both batch and streaming modes. Cloud Dataflow is a successor to MapReduce, and is based on our internal technologies like Flume and MillWheel. </p><p>       Cloud Dataflow makes it easy for you to get actionable insights from your data while lowering operational costs without the hassles of deploying, maintaining or scaling infrastructure. You can use Cloud Dataflow for use cases like ETL, batch data processing and streaming analytics, and it will automatically optimize, deploy and manage the code and resources required.</p></blockquote>
      </li>
      <li>Cloud montoring:
        <ul>
          <li>A monitoring tool to find and fix unusual behavior across your 
application stack.</li>
          <li>It provides metrics, dashboards and alerting for Google Cloud Platform
and several popular services like Apache, Nginx, MySQL, etc.</li>
          <li>Google’s earlier acquisition of <a href="https://www.stackdriver.com/">Stackdriver</a> 
could have enabled them to integrate their monitoring tool to create
this.</li>
        </ul>
      </li>
      <li>Cloud Trace and Cloud Debugger provide tools to debug and find performance
bottlenecks in a live application. </li>
      <li>In the demo at I/O, they set a watchpoint in a live application to
to debug a ‘live call’. </li>
      <li>
        <p>Google Cloud Save provides a simple API to developers for saving, retrieving
 and synchronizing user data on the cloud and across devices without the
 need of any server code.</p>
      </li>
      <li>Most of these services are still in private beta and will be launched 
soon</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="google-fit"></a><strong><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/25/google-fit-warms-up/">Google Fit</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>
        <p>Google Fit will be a set of APIs that will allow developers to sync data
across wearables and devices.</p>

        <blockquote><p>The dream here is the bundling of user fitness data, with the user’s permission, of course. And Google is not alone in this aspiration, with Apple’s HealthKit platform among the many products aiming to aggregate your health zeros and ones.</p></blockquote>
      </li>
      <li>The SDK will roll out in a couple of weeks</li>
      <li>They already have partnered with brands to provide integration with 
<a href="http://thenextweb.com/gadgets/2014/05/27/adidas-micoach-smart-ball-uses-sensors-companion-app-help-bend-like-beckham/">Adidas Smart
sensors</a>
and <a href="https://secure-nikeplus.nike.com/plus/what_is_fuel/">Nike Fuel</a>.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="cardboard"></a><strong><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/25/google-io-attendees-gifted-brand-new-android-wear-smartwatches/">Giveaways at Google IO and #Cardboard!</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>Google IO attendees will get to choose between LG’s G or Samsung’s Gear Live smartwatches
announced at the event itself.</li>
      <li>Moreover, they will also get Moto 360 when it becomes available later this
year.</li>
      <li>
        <p>Additionally, Google gave a <a href="https://developers.google.com/cardboard/">cardboard</a>
which turns <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/25/hands-on-with-googles-incredibly-clever-cardboard-virtual-reality-headset/">into a virtual reality headset</a>
powered by your Android Phone with <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.google.samples.apps.cardboarddemo">Cardboard app</a></p>

        <p><img src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2014/06/giffy-6.gif?w=300&amp;h=190" title="'Folding Cardboard'" /></p>

        <script type="text/javascript" src="http://pshared.5min.com/Scripts/PlayerSeed.js?sid=281&amp;width=560&amp;height=345&amp;playList=518288467"></script>

        <p><br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br />
<br /></p>

        <p>[In case the above video isn’t viewable, check it out <a href="http://techcrunch.com/video/google-io-cardboard-demo/518288467/">here</a>]</p>
      </li>
      <li>Fun Fact, Cardboard was made by an engineer at Google in the 20% time they
get for projects other than the company assigned task(s).</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ol>

<p> 
 </p>

<hr />
<p><em>‘<a href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/categories/tech-news">Tech News</a>’ is a series of articles where I attempt to share and summarize
recent developments in technology (and the related industry) that interest,
amaze and/or excite me. These would attempt to cover topics ranging from impressive 
apps to Google’s latest acquisition to jaw-dropping updates from SpaceX or Tesla Motors
and much more.</em></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tech News: Nest, Dash, Microsoft's Android, Yahoo Aviate, Storage wars, ...]]></title>
    <link href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/26/tech-news-nest-dash-storage-wars-android-aviate/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-26T01:30:24+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/26/tech-news-nest-dash-storage-wars-android-aviate</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ol>
  <li><a href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/26/tech-news-nest-dash-storage-wars-android-aviate/#google-nest">Google Makes its Nest at the center of The Smart Home</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/26/tech-news-nest-dash-storage-wars-android-aviate/#dash">Dash : A rising star among the smart driving apps</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/26/tech-news-nest-dash-storage-wars-android-aviate/#aviate">Yahoo Releases Aviate Homescreen For Android To Organize Your Life</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/26/tech-news-nest-dash-storage-wars-android-aviate/#nokia-x2">Microsoft launched its first Android smartphone, Nokia X2</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/26/tech-news-nest-dash-storage-wars-android-aviate/#onedrive">Microsoft doubles free OneDrive Storage</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/26/tech-news-nest-dash-storage-wars-android-aviate/#google-glass">Google Glass Goes On Sale Outside The US, in UK</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/26/tech-news-nest-dash-storage-wars-android-aviate/#glass-ram-upgrade">Google Glass gets 2GB RAM</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/26/tech-news-nest-dash-storage-wars-android-aviate/#twitter-experiment">Twitter is experimenting with a new way to retweet</a>        </li>
  <li><a href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/26/tech-news-nest-dash-storage-wars-android-aviate/#oculus-carbon">Oculus Acquires Carbon Design, The Team That Designed The Xbox 360 Controller</a></li>
</ol>

<!--more-->
<p> 
 </p>

<hr />

<ol>
  <li><a name="google-nest"></a><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/23/google-makes-its-nest-at-the-center-of-the-smart-home/">Google Makes Its Nest At The Center Of The Smart Home</a>
    <ul>
      <li>
        <p><a href="https://nest.com/works-with-nest">Works with Nest</a> is a program where
Nest (as an independent entity under Google) is allowing developers to
use Nest’s APIs to convey information to Nest and help create a ‘smart
home’ or ‘internet of things’. This video gives a good insight into their
vision and the direction they are headed.</p>

        <iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/bPdltu-93pM" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
      </li>
      <li>Several big names have associated with the program already
        <ul>
          <li>Mercedes-Benz
            <blockquote><p>Your car can tell Nest when you’ll be home so your thermostat can start heating or cooling at exactly the right time. It keeps you from wasting energy, and means you’re comfortable as soon as you walk in the door.</p></blockquote>
          </li>
          <li>
            <p>Whirlpool</p>

            <blockquote><p>If your Nest Thermostat notices you’re away, it can have Whirlpool switch to a refresh mode when your cycle ends, so your clothes stay fresh and wrinkle-free<br />          &#8230;<br />          If you’re signed up for Rush Hour Rewards with a participating energy provider, Nest can let Whirlpool know when an energy rush hour is about to happen, and your washer or dryer will delay the start of the cycle until the rush hour is over</p></blockquote>
          </li>
          <li>Charmberlain (garage automation)
            <blockquote><p>Open the garage when you arrive, and Chamberlain can tell Nest you’re home. Close it on your way out, and your thermostat can go into Away mode so you don’t waste energy heating or cooling an empty home.</p></blockquote>
          </li>
          <li>IFTTT
            <blockquote><p>Create your own connections with one simple statement – “if this then that.” For example, “If my Nest Protect detects smoke, then send a text message to my neighbors.”</p></blockquote>
          </li>
          <li>Google
            <blockquote><p>Just speak a command, “OK Google. Set the temperature to 75 degrees,” and your Nest Thermostat will do as you say. And with Google Now, you can be on your way home and your thermostat will start heating or cooling before you get there.</p></blockquote>
          </li>
        </ul>
      </li>
      <li>Nest, or Google, are not the only players in the smart-home segment. </li>
      <li>Apple had recently announced its own smarthome solution, <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/02/apple-wwdc-smart-home/">HomeKit</a></li>
      <li>
        <p><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/02/apple-wwdc-smart-home/">Quirky, too,
announced</a>
<a href="http://www.winkapp.com/">‘Wink’</a>, which is similar to ‘Works with Nest’.</p>

        <blockquote><p>[The idea] is to set up a platform that will allow consumers to control these various devices from an app which will operate as a dashboard of sorts for everything in their connected home.</p></blockquote>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="dash"></a> <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/24/with-a-series-of-upgrades-dash-becomes-a-viable-competitor-among-smart-driving-apps/">Dash : A rising star among the smart driving apps</a>
    <ul>
      <li><a href="https://dash.by/">Dash</a> is a combination of smart driving app and hardware device that 
offers real-time feedback on your driving, trip logs, vehicle diagnostics, etc.</li>
      <li>It is not the only product out there. Others include <a href="https://www.automatic.com/">Automatic</a>, <a href="http://www.carmd.com/">CarMD</a>, <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.prowl.torque&amp;hl=en">Torque</a> and (Pune-based) <a href="http://mycariq.com/">CarIQ</a></li>
      <li>These work by interacting with a <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00H9S71LW/ref=as_li_qf_sp_asin_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=B00H9S71LW&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=daslab-20">Bluetooth-enabled OBD(On-board
Diagnostics)
device</a> that can be plugged into a port in the car that supports it. Most
recent models do support OBD devices.</li>
      <li>Dash has recently released upgrades including integration with <a href="http://ifttt.com">IFTTT</a> and an API for third-party developers.</li>
      <li>With IFTTT integration, users can build simple recipes that help link
their car’s data with other tools like Google, Facebook, Evernote, Dropbox, etc.
        <blockquote><p>Designed for everything from fleet tracking to personal use, the first recipes include geo-fenced alerts, SMS alerts, Check Engine Light alerts, expense tracking, trip tracking, Do Not Disturb notifications (so you’re not bothered by incoming calls when driving), Google Glass integration, smart home integration, and more.</p></blockquote>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>Other improvements</p>

        <blockquote><p>In addition, Dash’s core product is seeing a number of improvements and changes too, including increased access to real-time data from more data points and gauges, a trends section that shows your Dash score, fuel efficiency/MPG and driving miles over time, automated VIN decoding (which lets the app recognize what car you’re currently plugged into), integration with automotive info site Edmunds, Android tablet support, and added support for dozens of new OBD devices and car models.</p><p>      Although Dash is now offering users more data to look through, the company is trying to balance that with a simplified interface, so it won’t be any more of a distraction to drivers than something like a radio or nav system.</p></blockquote>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="aviate"></a><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/23/yahoo-releases-aviate-homescreen-for-android-to-organize-your-life/">Yahoo Releases Aviate Homescreen For Android To Organize Your Life</a>
    <ul>
      <li>Aviate was acquired by <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/01/07/yahoo-announces-that-it-has-acquired-intelligent-homescreen-startup-aviate/">Yahoo in January</a></li>
      <li>It was an app that provided contextually relevant information on Android
homescreens.</li>
      <li>Now, Yahoo Aviate replaces the launcher in your phone to provide a smarter,
context aware interface.</li>
      <li>Based on the time of day and location, for instance, the app deduces whether
you need applications related to work or entertainment.</li>
      <li>
        <p>The most popular contacts are also, automatically, pulled to the favorites
list.</p>

        <iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/gj-cYb9eiRY" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

        <blockquote><p>Yahoo Aviate simplifies everything about your phone. It starts with a clean, new layout and apps automatically organized for you. But it’s not just about making your phone simpler – Aviate also makes your phone smarter by offering intelligent information throughout your day. Whether you’re on the go, at work, at a restaurant or just relaxing at home, Aviate automatically shows you apps and information that are useful to you based on what you’re up to</p></blockquote>
      </li>
      <li>It is quite like Google Now integrated well with the UI.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="nokia-x2"></a><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/24/nokia-x2/">Microsoft launched its first Android smartphone, Nokia X2</a>
    <ul>
      <li>While Nokia had earlier released Nokia X, it was unclear if Microsoft 
approved of Nokia’s Android experiment.</li>
      <li>
        <p>Nokia had forked Android in February to create a new smartphone platform,
Nokia X platform.</p>

        <blockquote><p>At the time Nokia described the fork as a Lumia “feeder” — with then CEO Stephen Elop saying Nokia X devices would be a Trojan horse within Google’s ecosystem by introducing first time smartphone owners to Microsoft’s services rather than Mountain View’s.</p></blockquote>
      </li>
      <li>Specs 
        <ul>
          <li>1.2GHz dual-core Snapdragon processor</li>
          <li>1GB RAM</li>
          <li>5MP camera</li>
          <li>4.3” screen</li>
        </ul>
      </li>
      <li>Processor and screen size are the primary improvements over the earlier <a href="http://www.nokia.com/global/products/nokia-x/">Nokia X</a></li>
      <li>Like Nokia X, this offers Windows like tile-based UI along with several
Microsoft/Nokia based Android apps like
<a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.skype.raider&amp;hl=en">Skype</a>,
<a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.microsoft.skydrive&amp;hl=en">OneDrive</a>,
<a href="http://here.com/">Here Maps</a> pre-installed.</li>
      <li>Dual SIM support, something popular in emerging markets.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="onedrive"></a><a href="http://www.theverge.com/2014/6/23/5833808/onedrive-free-storage-increase-pricing-productivity-war">Microsoft doubles free OneDrive Storage</a>
    <ul>
      <li>Free OneDrive storage increased from 7GB to 15GB</li>
      <li>All versions of <a href="">Office 365</a> will now come with 1TB of space, instead
of the earlier 20GB. Prices have been slashed across plans as well.</li>
      <li>
        <p>With these changes, Microsoft seems to have ‘kicked off’ a productivity
war with Google.</p>

        <blockquote><p>&#8220;Anyone can do storage,&#8221; explains Microsoft’s head of OneDrive product management Angus Logan. &#8220;When you think of bringing in the productivity … that’s just something that Microsoft alone can deliver. No other company can deliver that.&#8221;<br />      &#8230;<br />      &#8220;When you think about productivity or authoring, Google is kind of the closest in terms of that, but I still think they’re far away,&#8221; notes Logan.<br />      &#8230;<br />      &#8220;We don’t really think of this as a storage price war,&#8221; explains Logan. &#8220;What we’re actually thinking about is a productivity war.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="google-glass"></a><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/23/uk-glass">Google Glass goes on sale in UK</a>
    <ul>
      <li>Ahead of <a href="https://www.google.com/events/io">Google IO</a>, Google Glass goes
on sale in the UK. </li>
      <li>It is available for purchase on Google Play for residents of UK.</li>
      <li>It was opened up to ‘anyone’ in US back in April.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="glass-ram-upgrade"></a><a href="https://plus.google.com/+GoogleGlass/posts/1tSYsPCCsGf">Google Glass gets 2GB RAM</a>
    <ul>
      <li>Google announced that it will soon be shipping an upgraded Google Glass 
with 2GB of RAM.</li>
      <li>This comes in time for the UK launch.</li>
      <li>This has <a href="http://www.pcworld.com/article/2367800/googles-2gb-ram-upgrade-for-new-glass-explorers-angers-early-adopters.html">angered early
adopters</a>
who are stuck with 1GB of RAM</li>
      <li>Additional improvements/features, include 
        <ul>
          <li>“Ok Google glass, show the viewfinder”, brings the viewfinder or “
 white L’s in the four corners of [the] Glass screen”, making it 
 easier to frame the shots.</li>
          <li>Google Now cards to show where you parked your car and tracking shipments.</li>
          <li><a href="https://plus.google.com/+GoogleGlass/posts/UyJAnNgY7Kx">12 new ‘Glassware’ (apps for Google Glass)</a> 
including Guardian, Shazam, Duoling and Runtastic.</li>
        </ul>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="twitter-experiment"></a><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/24/twitter-is-experimenting-with-a-new-way-to-retweet">Twitter is experimenting with a new way to retweet</a>      <br />
    <ul>
      <li>Twitter currently allows the users to either direclty retweet a tweet
or ‘quote’ a tweet, allowing someone to tag someone or add some more text.</li>
      <li>However, even the quote retweet option requires the length of the entire
tweet to be under 140 characters, which can be quite restrictive.</li>
      <li>
        <p>Twitter is experimenting a new feature ‘Retweet with comments’ with a 
segment of its users.</p>

        <p><img class="center" src="http://rajatkhanduja.com/images/retweet-with-comment.jpg" title="&#34;Retweet with comment&#34;" alt="&#34;Retweet with comment&#34;" /></p>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="oculus-carbon"></a><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/24/oculus-acquires-carbon-design-the-team-that-designed-the-xbox-360-controller/">Oculus Acquires Carbon Design, The Team That Designed The Xbox 360 Controller</a>
    <ul>
      <li><a href="http://www.carbondesign.com">Carbon Design Studio</a> had designed XBox 360 controller and the original
Kinect.
        <blockquote><p>[T]urns out, Oculus has already been working with Carbon Design for sometime, though they won’t say on what. Just that they’ve “been working with Carbon for nearly a year on multiple unannounced projects.</p></blockquote>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ol>

<p> 
 </p>

<hr />
<p><em>‘<a href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/categories/tech-news">Tech News</a>’ is a series of articles where I attempt to share and summarize
recent developments in technology (and the related industry) that interest,
amaze and/or excite me. These would attempt to cover topics ranging from impressive 
apps to Google’s latest acquisition to jaw-dropping updates from SpaceX or Tesla Motors
and much more.</em></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tech News: Cruise, Baarzo, Google Domains, ...]]></title>
    <link href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/24/tech-news-cruise-baarzo-google-domains/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-24T22:30:30+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/24/tech-news-cruise-baarzo-google-domains</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ol>
  <li><a href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/24/tech-news-cruise-baarzo-google-domains/#cruise">For $10,000, your car can drive itself</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/24/tech-news-cruise-baarzo-google-domains/#laser-space">Laser message from space</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/24/tech-news-cruise-baarzo-google-domains/#google-domains">Google Domains (invite-only beta)</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/24/tech-news-cruise-baarzo-google-domains/#google-baarzo">Google may buy video search startup Baarzo</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/24/tech-news-cruise-baarzo-google-domains/#plaintext-passwd">Plaintext password offenders</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/24/tech-news-cruise-baarzo-google-domains/#lotus">Lotus: A complete webframework for Ruby</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/24/tech-news-cruise-baarzo-google-domains/#coders-high">Coder’s high</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/24/tech-news-cruise-baarzo-google-domains/#biggest-problems">We have the potential to solve the biggest problems of today</a>
<!--more--></li>
</ol>

<p> 
 </p>

<hr />

<ol>
  <li><a name="cruise"></a><strong><a href="http://www.theverge.com/2014/6/23/5834604/cruise-trying-to-reinvent-cruise-control-to-steer-brake-and-actually-drive-you">For $10,000, your car can drive
itself</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>Y combinator startup, Cruise Automation, has developed
<a href="http://www.getcruise.com/">Cruise</a>, an auto-pilot for your car.</li>
      <li>It is not really a ‘self-driving’ car yet.  &lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s<br />      designed as a computer-controlled driving system that can take over when<br />      you’re behind the wheel. Turn it on like typical cruise control and it<br />      will keep the car going, but the added smarts will steer, brake, and<br />      avoid objects.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</li>
      <li>Not meant to replace the driver and can’t drive independently from point
A to point B. However, it can steer through stretches of road, managing
lanes and avoiding obstacles.</li>
      <li>Quite cheap compared to the ‘fully-self-driving’ options. </li>
      <li>RP-1, a $10,000 <em>kit</em>, currently compatible with two Audi models, can be
installed in the car to let it ‘cruise’ intelligently.</li>
      <li>Grander plan of the company is to collect freeway data that is shared
between vehicles
and is constantly updated between them.</li>
      <li>The technology is still in its early stages.</li>
      <li>
        <p>With Cruise, they can capture road images, GPS and inertial measurements
as well. </p>

        <blockquote><p>The goal is to create white-listed areas of freeways where the system knows its way and Cruise can be enabled.</p></blockquote>
      </li>
      <li>CEO, Kyle Vogt 
        <ul>
          <li>cofounded <a href="http://www.justin.tv/">Justin.tv</a>, which allows anyone to
broadcast video online.</li>
          <li>cofounded <a href="http://www.twitch.tv/">Twitch</a>, a live streaming video platform 
focused on e-sports and video-gaming.</li>
        </ul>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="laser-space"></a><strong><a href="http://science.nasa.gov/science-news/science-at-nasa/2014/18jun_opals/">Laser message from space</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>OPALS (Optical Payload for Lasercomm Science) provides a new method 
of data communication at extremely high speeds.</li>
      <li>
        <p>As reported by <a href="http://gizmodo.com/nasa-used-a-space-laser-to-download-video-from-orbit-at-1587523627">Gizmodo</a> earlier, on 5th June when ISS passed 
over Table Mountain Observatory in Wrightwood, California, it beamed 
a video for researchers waiting below.</p>

        <blockquote><p>&#8230; the laser rig beamed down the &#8220;Hello, World&#8221; video shown below in a mere 3.5 seconds, a feat that would have taken more than 10 minutes using traditional radio frequencies currently used for data transmission to outer space.</p></blockquote>
      </li>
      <li>OPALS was launched to the space station on board a <a href="http://www.spacex.com/dragon">SpaceX Dragon spacecraft</a>
in the spring of 2014</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="google-domains"></a><strong><a href="http://www.theverge.com/2014/6/23/5835560/google-launches-domain-registration-service">Google Domains (invite-only beta)</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li><a href="http://domains.google.com/about/">Google Domains</a>, still in beta, offers 
a domain registry service, competing against the likes of <a href="http://godaddy.com/">GoDaddy</a>
and <a href="http://www.bigrock.in/">BigRock</a>.</li>
      <li>For hosting, however, they have partnered with Squarespace, Wix, Weebly, and Shopify</li>
      <li>
        <p>The benefits?</p>

        <blockquote><p>First, it&#8217;s promising not to charge users anything extra to conceal personal information (e.g. name and address) that must be provided when registering a URL. Google Domains users can create up to 100 email aliases using their domain, and Mountain View also says it&#8217;s making domain forwarding super easy in case there&#8217;s already a Tumblr or existing site you&#8217;d like your new URL to point to. And you shouldn&#8217;t run into any problems or downtime (at least on Google&#8217;s end). Google Domains use the same DNS servers as Google&#8217;s other websites, ensuring &#8220;your domain will connect quickly and reliably to your website.&#8221;</p><p>       Lastly, there&#8217;s the benefit of real customer support. Google says phone and email support will be available Monday through Friday from 9AM to 9PM EST</p></blockquote>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="google-baarzo"></a><strong><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/21/google-buying-baarzo/">Google may buy video search startup Baarzo</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>Baarzo’s technology description:
        <blockquote><p>Unlike Google or YouTube searches, which only evaluate the text around the video, the Baarzo search technology actually analyzes the video content, recognizing hundreds of thousands of objects and millions of faces, and locates the precise moment in the video when the search objects interact in the way you had specified.</p></blockquote>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>Although the acquisition details are not yet public and even the acquisition
isn’t confirmed, TechCrunch received information from Facebook posts, 
including those by <a href="https://www.facebook.com/IITG.Alumni/posts/672681839483630">IIT Guwahati Alumni Association page</a>.</p>

        <p><img src="https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2014/06/baarzo-facebook-screenshot.jpg?w=501&amp;h=508" title="&#34;Post by IIT Guwahati Alumni Association page [source: TechCrunch]&#34;" alt="&#34;Post by IIT Guwahati Alumni Association page [source: TechCrunch]&#34;" /></p>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="plaintext-passwd"></a><strong><a href="http://plaintextoffenders.com/">Plaintext password offenders</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>Storing passwords in plaintext is known to be an insecure way of dealing
with passwords, however, still
<a href="http://techland.time.com/2011/06/02/new-sony-hack-claims-one-million-user-passwords/">several</a>
<a href="http://blog.codinghorror.com/the-dirty-truth-about-web-passwords/">popular</a>
<a href="http://www.theregister.co.uk/2011/06/08/password_re_use_survey/">websites</a>
follow this archaic practice.</li>
      <li>This site tries to make a list of all such <em>offenders</em>. </li>
      <li><a href="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Password_Storage_Cheat_Sheet">Here’s a quick password storage
cheatsheet</a>
(read about the topics discussed here in more detail to be sure of what
you are doing)</li>
      <li>And here’s an interesting Coding horror blog : <a href="http://blog.codinghorror.com/youre-probably-storing-passwords-incorrectly/">You’re probably storing
passwords
incorrectly</a></li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="lotus"></a><strong><a href="http://lotusrb.org/">Lotus: A complete webframework for Ruby</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>From its author’s blog : 
        <blockquote><p>It’s a complete web framework, with a strong emphasis on object oriented design and testability. If you use Lotus, you employ less DSLs and more objects, zero monkey-patching, separation of concerns between MVC layers. Each library is designed to be small (under 500LOCs), fast and testable.<br />      &#8230;<br />      We have infinite combinations. Small components have enormous advantadges in terms of reusability.</p><p>      The power of these frameworks is combined together in Lotus applications.</p></blockquote>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="coders-high"></a><strong><a href="http://www.slate.com/articles/technology/technology/2014/06/coder_s_high_the_intense_feeling_of_absorption_exclusive_to_programmers.html">Coder’s high</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>An interesting reflection on the ‘intense feeling of absorption’
experienced while programming.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="biggest-problems"></a><strong><a href="http://www.christophmccann.com/blog/2014/6/23/we-have-the-potential-to-solve-the-biggest-problems-of-today">We have the potential to solve the biggest problems of today</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>This article takes a dig at the apps like <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/18/yo-yo/">Yo</a>.</li>
      <li>Yo, which recently got a $1.2 million in funding, has been raising
doubts and questions in its utility and worth.</li>
      <li>Used to send just two letters, ‘Yo’, the app has 50,000 active users 
who have sent 4 million “Yo’s” across.</li>
      <li>The article discusses that we should be focusing on more important issues
and how making another instant messaging app is not going to tackle 
the major issues of the world.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ol>

<p> 
 </p>

<hr />
<p><em>‘<a href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/categories/tech-news">Tech News</a>’ is a series of articles where I attempt to share and summarize
recent developments in technology (and the related industry) that interest,
amaze and/or excite me. These would attempt to cover topics ranging from impressive 
apps to Google’s latest acquisition to jaw-dropping updates from SpaceX or Tesla Motors
and much more.</em></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tech News: Wearable computing, Cgrep, Web Starter Kit, ... ]]></title>
    <link href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/21/tech-news-wearable-computing-cgrep-web-starter-kit/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-21T23:30:20+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/21/tech-news-wearable-computing-cgrep-web-starter-kit</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ol>
  <li><a href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/21/tech-news-wearable-computing-cgrep-web-starter-kit/#passive-haptic-learning">Using Wearable Computers for Passive Haptic Learning and Rehabilitation</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/21/tech-news-wearable-computing-cgrep-web-starter-kit/#cgrep">Cgrep: a context-aware grep for source codes</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/21/tech-news-wearable-computing-cgrep-web-starter-kit/#nest-dropcam">Google backed Nest acquires Dropcam</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/21/tech-news-wearable-computing-cgrep-web-starter-kit/#google-block-sites">B.C. court ruling orders Google to block sites worldwide</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/21/tech-news-wearable-computing-cgrep-web-starter-kit/#google-web-starter-kit">Google launches starter kit for a more consistent web</a></li>
</ol>

<p>External links (not summarized below):</p>

<ol>
  <li><a href="https://blog.ethereum.org/2014/06/19/mining/">Discussion on possible solution of the GHash problem in Bitcoin network</a> 
 (would try to summarize this in a later post)</li>
  <li><a href="https://medium.com/the-physics-arxiv-blog/quantum-experiment-shows-how-time-emerges-from-entanglement-d5d3dc850933">Quantum Experiment Shows How Time ‘Emerges’ from Entanglement</a></li>
</ol>

<!--more-->

<p> 
 </p>

<hr />

<ol>
  <li><a name="passive-haptic-learning"></a><a href="https://plus.google.com/+ResearchatGoogle/posts/EgtfWJME37g">Using Wearable Computers for Passive Haptic Learning and Rehabilitation</a>
    <ul>
      <li>At Georgia Institute of Technology, a wireless glove, Mobile Music Touch (MMT),
has been developed that enables users to learn to play piano melodies while 
performing everyday tasks. </li>
      <li>The process is called ‘Passive Haptic Learning’.
        <blockquote><p>Vibration motors are embedded in the glove at the base of each finger and the thumb.  The song being learned can be loaded onto a user’s mobile phone and is played as they go about their business.  As each note is played, the glove taps the finger corresponding to the appropriate key on a piano keyboard.  The result: in as little as 30 minutes, the user learns the &#8220;muscle memory&#8221; of the first phrases of the song, even if their attention has been devoted to another task.</p></blockquote>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>Even when distracted while the MMT tapped their fingers by tasks, like reading
emails, taking a graduate entrance exam and watching a movie, the subjects
were able to learn to play the songs.</p>

        <blockquote><p>Surprisingly, only the vibration was needed for the glove to be effective&#8211; on average, participants who only &#8220;felt&#8221; the music performed as well as those who heard the audio concurrently.</p></blockquote>
      </li>
      <li>Experiments suggest that it can also use in rehabilitation to help those
with paralysis because of spinal injuries.</li>
    </ul>

    <iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/Zi6t89pi17c" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
  </li>
  <li><a name="cgrep"></a><a href="http://awgn.github.io/cgrep/">Cgrep: a context-aware grep for source codes</a>
    <ul>
      <li>Grep tool for large code repositories</li>
      <li>Searches beyond simple pattern matching
        <ul>
          <li>Allows search in comments or code (except comment)</li>
          <li>Allows searching in string literals</li>
        </ul>
      </li>
      <li>Claims to have semantic search capability</li>
      <li><a href="http://beyondgrep.com/why-ack/">Ack</a> is another tool relevant for 
grepping through source code. Doesn’t have any semantic search capability</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="nest-dropcam"></a><a href="https://nest.com/blog/2014/06/20/the-nest-family-is-growing/">Google backed Nest acquires Dropcam</a>
    <ul>
      <li>Dropcam provides wifi connected camera setup to allow its customers to install
in their houses, so that they can check in on their home, irrespective 
of where they are in the world.</li>
      <li>Dropcam can be used to keep tabs on doors, windows or valuables at home. 
Even useful as a child monitoring tool.</li>
      <li>Nest, the company that creates intelligent thermostats, was acquired 
by Google recently. </li>
      <li>Like Nest’s acquisition by Google, this raises some privacy concerns. </li>
      <li>Probably to stave off thoughts like, “Now Google gets a video feed in 
my house!”, Nest explains in it’s blogpost that
        <blockquote><p>Once the deal closes, we’ll incorporate Dropcam into how we do business at Nest. That includes how we handle everything from customer support to customer privacy. Like Nest customer data, Dropcam will come under Nest’s privacy policy, which explains that data won’t be shared with anyone (including Google) without a customer’s permission. Nest has a paid-for business model and ads are not part of our strategy. In acquiring Dropcam, we’ll apply that same policy to Dropcam too.</p></blockquote>
      </li>
      <li>The numbers are not stated on their blogpost, but sources like <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/20/google-and-nest-acquire-dropcam-for-555-million/">techrunch</a>
quote a figure of $555m for the acquisition.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="google-block-sites"></a><a href="http://www.theglobeandmail.com/report-on-business/industry-news/the-law-page/bc-court-seeking-global-reach-orders-google-to-block-sites/article19212708/">B.C. court ruling orders Google to block sites worldwide</a>
    <ul>
      <li>A British Columbia court ordered Google (temporary injunction) to block
certain websites from ‘worldwide search engine’</li>
      <li>This raises the question of how much control can a country’s court exert 
on the Internet.</li>
      <li>The case in discussion involves a company whose trade secrets were stollen 
to create a competing product, which is being sold through a network 
of websites despite several court orders.</li>
      <li>While current procedures allow Google to block search results within 
Canada, since most sales occur outside Canada, they have been asked to 
block the site across the entire system. </li>
      <li></li>
    </ul>
    <blockquote><p>But University of Ottawa law professor Michael Geist slammed the recent Google decision in a blog post on Tuesday, warning that it could lead to other countries demanding Google censor content worldwide, putting free speech at risk. “While the court does not grapple with this possibility, what happens if a Russian court orders Google to remove gay and lesbian sites from its database? Or if Iran orders it remove Israeli sites from the database?”</p></blockquote>
    <ul>
      <li>Earlier, EU enforced Google to honor <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/05/30/right-to-be-forgotten-webform/">‘Right to be
forgotten’</a>
for its own citizens, which allows users to <a href="https://support.google.com/legal/contact/lr_eudpa?product=websearch#">request removal of
pages/information from Google’s indexes</a>.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="google-web-starter-kit"></a><a href="http://readwrite.com/2014/06/19/google-launches-starter-kit-for-a-more-consistent-web">Google launches starter kit for a more consistent web</a>
    <ul>
      <li>With the different kind of devices, people expect the same website to 
behave differently depending on the device (touchscreen vs desktop, 
mobile vs tablet)</li>
      <li><a href="https://developers.google.com/web/starter-kit/">Web Starter Kit</a> 
provides a boilerplate for developers to get started with multi-device 
development. </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ol>

<p> 
 </p>

<hr />
<p><em>‘<a href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/categories/tech-news">Tech News</a>’ is a series of articles where I attempt to share and summarize
recent developments in technology (and the related industry) that interest,
amaze and/or excite me. These would attempt to cover topics ranging from impressive 
apps to Google’s latest acquisition to jaw-dropping updates from SpaceX or Tesla Motors
and much more.</em></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tech News: Facebook's engineering & outage, CodeSpaces, SpaceX,...]]></title>
    <link href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/20/tech-news-facebook-codespace-spacex/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-20T23:43:54+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/20/tech-news-facebook-codespace-spacex</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ol>
  <li><a href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/20/tech-news-facebook-codespace-spacex/#fb-network-switch">Facebook breaks the network switch into modules</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/20/tech-news-facebook-codespace-spacex/#fb-android">Facebook Saves Developing World’s Data Plans With 65% Smaller, 50% More Efficient Android App</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/20/tech-news-facebook-codespace-spacex/#fb-outage">Facebook outage; down for around 30 minutes</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/20/tech-news-facebook-codespace-spacex/#codespaces">Code Spaces destroyed after attacked deletes Amazon-hosted data</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/20/tech-news-facebook-codespace-spacex/#mars-spacex">Elon Musk: Hopeful that the first people could be taken to Mars in 10 to 12 years</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/20/tech-news-facebook-codespace-spacex/#skype">Skype for Linux 4.3 Arrives with Desktop Call Monitor Widget, UI Changes</a></li>
</ol>

<!--more-->
<p> 
 </p>

<hr />

<ol>
  <li><a name="fb-network-switch"></a><strong><a href="http://www.datacenterknowledge.com/archives/2014/06/18/facebook-breaks-network-switch-modules/">Facebook breaks the network switch into modules</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>Facebook has been trying to disaggregate mains parts of their data center
to provide more flexibility. Components can be separately upgraded and
congigured for optimal performance.</li>
      <li>Until now, they had succeeded with compute, server and storage, but the
traditional switches were being used.</li>
      <li>Wedge, the new top-of-rack switch, breaks that.</li>
      <li>Hardware and software components are broken into modules.
        <blockquote><p>The central modular hardware feature of Wedge is the OCP “Group Hug” motherboard, originally developed for microservers. A single Group Hug board can accommodate Intel, AMD or ARM processors.</p><p>      Besides configurability, using a server board makes the box behave less like a switch and more like a server. “It basically takes the switch and it turns the switch into … another server,” Parikh said.</p></blockquote>
      </li>
      <li>Facebook also designed FBOSS, a linux based OS, to make use of libraries
and systems to manage their fleet of servers.
        <blockquote><p>FBOSS also puts an abstraction layer on top of the ASIC APIs of the switch which enables its engineers to treat it like they treat any other service in Facebook. “With FBOSS, all our infrastructure software engineers instantly become network engineers,” Bachar and Simpkins wrote.</p></blockquote>
      </li>
      <li>The design of the data switch will eventually be shared as part of its
<a href="http://www.opencompute.org/">Open Compute Project</a></li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="fb-android"></a><strong><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/19/facebook-for-android/">Facebook Saves Developing World’s Data Plans With 65% Smaller, 50% More Efficient Android App</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>Having reached most of the market in the developed countries, Facebook is
trying to reach out in the emerging markets.</li>
      <li>While Android is a good platform for that, it also poses the issue that 
these markets have several low-end devices and expensive data plans. </li>
      <li><a href="https://code.facebook.com/posts/485459238254631/improving-facebook-on-android">Facebook has improved their Android app to counter these problems</a>
        <blockquote><p>To help accomplish this goal, a team of product managers and engineers traveled to Africa to examine mobile performance in developing countries. We purchased several different Android handsets to test the latest version of the Facebook app – and the testing process proved to be difficult. The combination of an intermittent, low-bandwidth network connection and a lack of memory space on the devices resulted in slow load times and constant crashes. We even burned through our monthly data plans in 40 minutes.</p></blockquote>
      </li>
      <li>Performance (start times reduced by more than 50%)
        <blockquote><p>we found that start times were slower on single-core devices because too many features concurrently initialized themselves on application startup. We made sure to defer these initializations until after startup and, in some cases, until the features are used.</p><p>        We also wanted the stories in News Feed to load faster. In order to rapidly display cached content on poor networks, we now fetch stories earlier in the process to allow more time to set up connections and download News Feed. The cold start path has been automated to ensure that we prevent further regressions in these areas.</p></blockquote>
      </li>
      <li>Data efficiency (because data is expensive in developing countries)
        <ul>
          <li>After trying alternatives, settled on WebP compression format for
image transmission.</li>
        </ul>
        <blockquote><p>The use of WebP for transmitting Facebook images resulted in data savings of 25 to 35 percent compared with JPG, and 80 percent compared with PNG. This all happened without perceived impact on quality.</p></blockquote>
        <ul>
          <li>Instead of loading images at high resolution, load only resolution
equivalent to the size of the viewport in which the images will appear.</li>
          <li>Higher resolution image requested/downloaded only when someone wants
to zoom-in on an image.</li>
          <li>Fine tuned caching strategies and sizes to minimize evictions for 
images that could be accessed again.</li>
        </ul>
        <blockquote><p>The work on data efficiency resulted in a 50 percent reduction in data use compared with earlier last year.</p></blockquote>
      </li>
      <li>Networking
        <ul>
          <li>Current stack (<a href="http://square.github.io/okhttp/">OkHttp</a>) allowed
fast retries for intermittent network situations.</li>
          <li>Tried to decrease the number of reports regarding failed image loads
in News Feed. </li>
          <li>Fine tuned image pre-fetching algorithms and altered the process through
which the images are queued for download. </li>
          <li>Ensured that the images expected to be downloaded next are prioritized and no image
is stuck in queue for long.</li>
        </ul>
        <blockquote><p>In combination with better data usage for images, reports of slow or failed image loads dropped by almost 90 percent over the past year.</p></blockquote>
      </li>
      <li>Application size
        <ul>
          <li>Reduced application size by using Google Play’s options to provide 
different APKs for different OS versions and screen resolutions.</li>
          <li>Code of features or resources not supported on certain devices have
been excluded to reduce the size of the app.</li>
        </ul>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="fb-outage"></a><strong><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/19/facebook-goes-down-in-global-outage/">Facebook outage; down for around 30 minutes</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>Apparently, this was not because of any attack on the system, but because
of an internal error. </li>
      <li>
        <p>Statement from Facebook</p>

        <blockquote><p>Late last night, we ran into an issue while updating the configuration of one of our software systems. Not long after we made the change, some people started to have trouble accessing Facebook. We quickly spotted and fixed the problem, and in less than 30 minutes Facebook was back to 100% for everyone. This doesn’t happen often, but when it does we make sure we learn from the experience so we can make Facebook that much more reliable. Nothing is more important to us than making sure Facebook is there when people need it, and we apologize to anyone who may have had trouble connecting last night.</p></blockquote>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="codespaces"></a><strong><a href="http://www.theregister.co.uk/2014/06/18/code_spaces_destroyed/">Code Spaces destroyed after attacked deletes Amazon-hosted data</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>Code Spaces, a source code hosting provider, has <a href="http://www.codespaces.com/?hackernews">posted the details of the attack</a>
that has caused them to go out of business.</li>
      <li>A DDOS attack started on 17th June and a hacker, who also gained access
to their Amazon EC2 control panel, left an email address for them to contact
through which they demanded a large some of money to stop the attack.</li>
      <li>
        <p>While their team tried to mitigate the attack and tried to regain control
of their control panel, the hacker caused a lot of damage.</p>

        <blockquote><p>At this point we took action to take control back of our panel by changing passwords, however the intruder had prepared for this and had already created a number of backup logins to the panel and upon seeing us make the attempted recovery of the account he proceeded to randomly delete artifacts from the panel. We finally managed to get our panel access back but not before he had removed all EBS snapshots, S3 buckets, all AMI&#8217;s, some EBS instances and several machine instances.</p><p>      In summary, most of our data, backups, machine configurations and offsite backups were either partially or completely deleted.</p></blockquote>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>As a consequence, …</p>

        <blockquote><p>Code Spaces will not be able to operate beyond this point, the cost of resolving this issue to date and the expected cost of refunding customers who have been left without the service they paid for will put Code Spaces in a irreversible position both financially and in terms of on going credibility.</p><p>      As such at this point in time we have no alternative but to cease trading and concentrate on supporting our affected customers in exporting any remaining data they have left with us</p></blockquote>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="mars-spacex"></a><strong><a href="http://www.nbcnews.com/science/space/elon-musk-promises-spacex-will-stay-course-mars-n133971">Elon Musk: Hopeful that the first people could be taken to Mars in 10 to 12 years</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dragon_%28spacecraft%29#Dragon_V2">Dragon V2</a>,
the second version of Dragon, is a fully reusable spacecraft (unlike 
Dragon, which was ‘partially’ reusable) and can carry up to 7 astronauts.</li>
      <li>
        <p>SpaceX is competing for a contract with NASA to deliver some crew transport
missions to International Space Station.</p>

        <blockquote><p>[Elon Musk] noted that SpaceX&#8217;s progression would be slowed down if the U.S. government doesn&#8217;t choose the company&#8217;s Dragon V2 as the next crew carrier to the International Space Station.</p></blockquote>
      </li>
      <li>Focus on Mars
        <blockquote><p>For now, he says the company is focused on creating technology that with enable large groups of people to travel to Mars.</p><p>      &#8220;I&#8217;m hopeful that the first people could be taken to Mars in 10 to 12 years, I think it&#8217;s certainly possible for that to occur,&#8221; he said. &#8220;But the thing that matters long term is to have a self-sustaining city on Mars, to make life multiplanetary.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="skype"></a><strong><a href="http://www.omgubuntu.co.uk/2014/06/download-skype-4-3-linux-new-ui-download">Skype for Linux 4.3 Arrives with Desktop Call Monitor Widget, UI Changes</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>Majorly UI improvements</li>
      <li>Provides better desktop integration and some features that were already
present in the Windows and Mac versions, like Desktop integration
for notifications.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ol>

<p> 
 </p>

<hr />
<p><em>‘<a href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/categories/tech-news">Tech News</a>’ is a series of articles where I attempt to share and summarize
recent developments in technology (and the related industry) that interest,
amaze and/or excite me. These would attempt to cover topics ranging from impressive 
apps to Google’s latest acquisition to jaw-dropping updates from SpaceX or Tesla Motors
and much more.</em></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tech News: Amazon announces new phone 'Fire']]></title>
    <link href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/19/tech-news-amazon-announces-new-phone-fire/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-19T00:31:53+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/19/tech-news-amazon-announces-new-phone-fire</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ol>
  <li><strong><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/18/amazon-announces-the-fire-phone/">Amazon announces Fire Phone : First phone with head-tracking tech</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>4.7 inch screen, Quad core 2.2GHz, Adreno 330 graphics, 2GB RAM.</li>
      <li>Runs FireOS, a fork of Android.</li>
      <li><a href="http://www.amazon.com/dp/B00EOE0WKQ">Available on contract with AT&amp;T for two years; starting $199</a></li>
      <li>While the hardware is not exceptional, its ability to track user’s 
head is what makes it different from the rest.
        <blockquote><p>This is done through four corner-mounted, front-facing infrared cameras and produces wild 3D effects. But it’s not tradition 3D in the sense that images pop out the screen. The head tracking tech adds depth to the phone. It’s like looking down a street. But into your phone’s screen.</p></blockquote>
      </li>
      <li>Using the head-tracking capability, Amazon built Dynamic Perspective,
which allows a 3D image viewing experience in the phone. [<a href="#dynamic_perspective">Read more
below</a>]</li>
      <li>Fire and Prime
        <blockquote><p>Amazon has built this phone for the Prime subscriber. Much like with the Fire TV, the Fire Phone will ship with a person’s Prime information already entered. The phone is, after all, all about selling more wares and Amazon is ensuring there are no barriers to entry for its best customers, those who subscribe to Prime. It also includes the personalized customer support service Mayday that debuted on the Kindle Fire.</p></blockquote>
      </li>
      <li>Fire phone comes preloaed with a feature called ‘Firefly’ (<a href="#firefly">read about it
below</a>).</li>
      <li>13MP campera. The quality of the photos compares with those from Samsung
Galaxy S5 and iPhone 5S (<a href="#camera">Read more about the camera below</a>).</li>
      <li>Comes loaded with popular music streaming apps :
<a href="http://www.spotify.com/">Spotify</a> and
<a href="http://www.pandora.com/">Pandora</a>. Not restricted to Amazon Prime Music</li>
      <li>
        <p><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/18/amazons-mayday-service-on-fire-phone-means-it-might-be-able-to-sell-its-unique-new-features/">Mayday, which allows customers to interact with service agents over
phone or video chat in just one-tap, is also available on Fire Phone</a></p>
      </li>
      <li>Mayday would make it easier for customers to work with unfamiliar
features.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="dynamic_perspective"></a><strong><a href="http://www.cnet.com/news/amazon-fire-phone-dynamic-perspective/">Amazon Fire Phone’s Dynamic Perspective offers a new angle on smartphone
displays</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>Amazon introduces a new way to experience a smartphone by using 3D
effects.
        <blockquote><p>Instead of creating the illusion that an object is coming right for you, you&#8217;re given a, well, dynamic perspective on things. Look at a lockscreen picture of a forest, or egyptian ruins, and you&#8217;re given a chance to peer behind or around some of the objects on screen. For a more practical application, consider the maps: during the presentation, Amazon CEO Jeff Bezos tilted the phone to pan about the map, getting a better angle on details like a particular street&#8217;s name. Tilt the phone gently, and you&#8217;ll pull up Yelp info and reviews.</p><p>      Or maybe you like shopping &#8211; in one example, Bezos pulls up a line of dresses on Amazon, and tilts the phone to scroll through the stack. Reading more to your liking? Just tilt the phone to scroll up and down a web page or e-book. You can even set things to autoscroll at a deliberate pace, essentially putting your literature on cruise control &#8211; drop a thumb to pause i</p></blockquote>
      </li>
      <li><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/18/amazon-phone-live-blog/#liveblog-entry-534596">Field of view of a single front-facing camera is too narrow to track 
user’s head</a></li>
      <li>Fire Phone uses 4 cameras mounted on the corners to track head and eyes.</li>
      <li>The company collected a lot of images of faces and applied machine 
learning to perfect the tracking capabilities.</li>
      <li><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/18/amazon-phone-live-blog/#liveblog-entry-534606">Dynamic Perspective SDK is available</a></li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="firefly"></a> <strong><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/18/amazons-fire-phone-introduces-firefly-a-feature-that-lets-you-identify-and-buy-things-you-see-the-real-world/">Fire phone introduces ‘Firefly’</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>A feature that lets you identify things that you see in the real world.</li>
      <li>You can also directly buy off using this.
        <blockquote><p>During the demonstration on stage, Amazon CEO Jeff Bezos showed off how Firefly can be used to scan barcodes on items, a book cover, a CD and more. There’s a Shazam-like audio recognition component as well – Firefly can identify songs, and it can even listen to a show, and then let you access that specific scene on Amazon, which is a clever trick.<br />      &#8230;.<br />      Firefly can also recognize art, and then pull up the associated Wikpedia entry, something Apple’s Siri and Google Now can’t yet do.</p><p>      At launch, Firefly is capable of recognizing over 100 million items, said Bezos. That includes 245,000 movies and TV episodes, 160 live TV channels, 35 million songs and 70 million product</p></blockquote>
      </li>
      <li>There is a dedicated button on the phone (besides the volume rocker) for
Firefly!
<img src="http://rajatkhanduja.com/images/firefly_button.jpg" title="&#34;Dedicated Firefly button&#34;" alt="&#34;Dedicated Firefly button&#34;" /></li>
      <li>Firefly looks like an extension of Flow, Amazon’s visual-recognition
technology that used to reside in its own standalone mobile app.</li>
      <li>When pointed at a sign board, it can identify the number (using
image-to-text) and determine if a phone number doesn’t exist, or 
directly call/save the number on the sign board.</li>
      <li>Firefly SDK will also be available, including text, audio and image
recognizers, content databases and support for custom actions allowing
developers to bend Firefly to their own personal needs.</li>
      <li>MyFitnessPal created an app, using the SDK, to find the nutritional value
of food item seen through the camera.</li>
      <li>The ability to recognize objects/entities through the camera lens 
of a phone would significantly benefit Amazon as identification 
is the first step in the purchasing process.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="camera"></a><strong><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/18/the-cloud-is-key-to-the-amazon-fires-ambitious-plan-to-win-over-smartphone-photographers/">Fire phone’s camera and unlimited cloud storage, for free!</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>Amazon Fire Phone hosts a 13MP camera</li>
      <li>Side-by-side shots show that the images are comparable to those from
iPhone 5S and Samsung Galaxy S5. However, it’d be best to wait until more
reviews pour in or try out yourself before commenting on the camera
quality.</li>
      <li>There’s a dedicated camera button, allowing users to jump to camera
directly by clicking the button (without unlocking the phone or searching
for the app)</li>
      <li>One click opens the camera app, second takes a photo.</li>
      <li>Unlimited storage on Amazon Cloud Drive
        <blockquote><p>Each Fire Phone comes with unlimited uploads and storage to Amazon Cloud Drive, for life, for free. There are no conditions on that offer, which makes it much more attractive than either the paid offering from Amazon (iCloud Photos) or Google’s Drive offerings, which also use paid tiers to limit how much you can upload at once.</p></blockquote>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ol>

<p> 
 </p>

<hr />
<p><em>‘<a href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/categories/tech-news">Tech News</a>’ is a series of articles where I attempt to share and summarize
recent developments in technology (and the related industry) that interest,
amaze and/or excite me. These would attempt to cover topics ranging from impressive 
apps to Google’s latest acquisition to jaw-dropping updates from SpaceX or Tesla Motors
and much more.</em></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tech News: Slingshot, JS Cryptography, Dropbox, ...]]></title>
    <link href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/18/tech-news-slingshot/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-18T23:22:07+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/18/tech-news-slingshot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ol>
  <li><strong><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/17/facebook-slingshot/">Facebook’s Slingshot challenges SnapChat with ‘Reply to Unlock’</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>Facebook’s new app <a href="http://www.sling.me/">Slingshot</a> is being seen as a 
competitor to SnapChat. </li>
      <li>It lets you share photos and 15-second videos with users on Slingshot.</li>
      <li>
        <p>The content is meant to be ephemeral, much like SnapChat. </p>

        <blockquote><p>As for what happens to your content, once everyone you’ve slinged something to views it, Facebook says it will delete the photo or video from its servers. There is a seven-day delay in case it has to investigate abuse reports, but the team says the content is gone after that. Whether users trust Facebook to keep its word is up to them. Past privacy missteps might scare people, but Facebook is under close scrutiny from the FTC to abide by the privacy policies it puts forward.</p></blockquote>
      </li>
      <li>An important catch in the app is that you can’t view the content shared 
by the user until you reply to it. (‘Reply to Unlock’)</li>
      <li>This aims to increase reciprocation and make everyone a content generator.</li>
      <li>Slingshot was born out of a hackathon. The motivation can be summarized by 
        <blockquote><p>“My brothers are really not technical in any way”, Slingshot inventor and four-year Facebook Product Designer Joey Flynn tells me. “I’d take a photo, upload it in iMessage, and send it to them. And I would just see “Seen”, or in a month I’d see them and they‘d say ‘that was a cool photo’. But hey, I want to see what you’re up to! There was this missing reciprocation” he explains. That was the spark for Slingshot.</p></blockquote>
      </li>
      <li>This app was <a href="http://mashable.com/2014/06/09/slingshot-app/">earlier released on app stored by mistake</a></li>
      <li>Facebook had tried to buy off SnapChat, but <a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2013/11/13/us-facebook-snapchat-idUSBRE9AC11E20131113">SnapChat had rejected the $3 billion buyout offer</a></li>
    </ul>

    <iframe src="//player.vimeo.com/video/98214265" width="500" height="400" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong><a href="http://matasano.com/articles/javascript-cryptography/">Browser based javascript cryptography considered harmful</a></strong></p>

    <p>Some of the things pointed out in the article. <em>[Not being an expert in cryptography, I would recommend readers to read
   the original article to avoid any miscommunication]</em></p>

    <ul>
      <li>Code could be injected when in transit. Can use SSL/TLS to avoid that, but 
then, in most cases, you could simply avoid cryptography at 
user end.</li>
      <li>There’s no certainty of information being removed from memory.</li>
      <li>It is not possible to verify the code/environment to be exactly as it is 
required to be. </li>
      <li>Javascript lacks a Cryptographically Secure Pseudo-Random Number Generator (CSPRNG). </li>
      <li><a href="https://crypto.stanford.edu/sjcl/">Stanford Javascript Crypto library (SJCL)</a>
developed at Stanford is a great work, but still insecure.
        <blockquote><p>The authors of SJCL themselves say, &#8220;Unfortunately, this is not as great as in desktop applications because it is not feasible to completely protect against code injection, malicious servers and side-channel attacks.&#8221; That last example is a killer: what they&#8217;re really saying is, &#8220;we don&#8217;t know enough about Javascript runtimes to know whether we can securely host cryptography on them&#8221;. Again, that&#8217;s painful-but-tolerable in a server-side application, where you can always call out to native code as a workaround. It&#8217;s death to a browser.</p></blockquote>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><strong><a href="https://www.privacyinternational.org/press-releases/uk-intelligence-forced-to-reveal-secret-policy-for-mass-surveillance-of-residents">UK intelligence forced to reveal secret policy for mass surveillance of
residents’ Facebook and Google
use</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>Secret policy define UK residents’ communication on Facebook, Google, Twitter, etc.
as ‘external communication’ because they use platforms based in the US, even
if the communication is between two people in the UK.</li>
      <li>This grants the secret services to indiscriminately intercept communication
on these platforms.</li>
      <li>For an ‘internal communication’, a warrant would be required, however that 
is not the case with ‘external communication’.
        <blockquote><p>The Government believes that, even when privacy violations happen, it is not an “active intrusion” because the analyst reading or listening to an individual’s communication will inevitably forget about it anyway.</p></blockquote>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><strong><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/16/dropbox-has-quietly-acquired-parastructure-a-big-data-startup-in-stealth/">Dropbox acquired Parastructure, a Big Data Startup</a></strong>
 -
    <blockquote><p>So what exactly is Parastructure? According to the company’s LinkedIn profile, and its (now-offline) home page, it builds “beautiful data analysis software powered by cutting-edge open source infrastructure.” Parastructure’s GitHub pages give some clues as to what that data-analysis software was tackling, with areas covering Spark for cluster computing; Phoenix, a SQL skin over HBase; CrunchBase; and so on</p></blockquote>

    <ul>
      <li>The acquisition was done quite stealthily.</li>
      <li>Probably, Dropbox requires the software and the team to analyze its data</li>
      <li>Parastructure was an enterprise oriented startup and its acquisition indicates 
Dropbox’s intention on strengthening their image as an enterprise product.</li>
      <li>Dropbox’s increased effort in <a href="https://www.dropbox.com/business">Dropbox for
Business</a> brings it in direct
competition with Box, which is currently leading as an enterprise
solution.</li>
      <li>Both the companies are quite aggressively acquiring companies. </li>
      <li>In fact, Parastructure was acquired on the same day as 
<a href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/17/tech-news-about-qeexos-fingersense-wristify-loon/">Box acquired Streem</a></li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><strong><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/18/apple-adds-a-new-entry-level-imac-for-1099/">Apple adds a new entry level iMac for ~$1,100</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>1.4GHz dual-core Intel Core i5 processor, 8GB memory, 500GB HDD, Intel HD Graphics 5000 on board
 
 </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ol>

<hr />
<p><em>‘<a href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/categories/tech-news">Tech News</a>’ is a series of articles where I attempt to share and summarize
recent developments in technology (and the related industry) that interest,
amaze and/or excite me. These would attempt to cover topics ranging from impressive 
apps to Google’s latest acquisition to jaw-dropping updates from SpaceX or Tesla Motors
and much more.</em></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tech News: About Qeexo's Fingersense, Wristify, Loon, ...]]></title>
    <link href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/17/tech-news-about-qeexos-fingersense-wristify-loon/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-17T23:06:39+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/17/tech-news-about-qeexos-fingersense-wristify-loon</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ol>
  <li><strong><a href="http://www.wired.com/2014/06/qeexo">Qeexo, a startup, is trying to redefine how we use touchscreens</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>Since the unveiling of iPhone, 7 years ago, not much has changed in how 
we interact with touchscreens.</li>
      <li>
        <p>Qeexo has developed a touchscreen technology capable of detecting difference
between a fingertip, a knuckle, fingernail and a stylus.</p>

        <blockquote><p>Today, FingerSense uses the standard accelerometer in a mobile device to pick up on the vibration patterns different parts of the hand produce when they come in contact with a touchscreen. The FingerSense machine-learning engine understands what part of the finger is touching the screen and triggers a correlated action. For instance, tapping a block of text with your knuckle could trigger the copy and paste menu to appear. To select text, you’d simply drag your knuckle down the text,much like you would a desktop mouse.</p></blockquote>
        <!--more-->
      </li>
      <li>However, to be able to make an impact, the startup would need to be able 
 to convince the giants like Apple and Samsung to not only change the way
 touchscreen works, but also agree upon standards to make sure the same 
 gesture has similar behavior across devices.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><strong><a href="http://www.wired.com/2013/10/an-ingenious-wristband-that-keeps-your-body-at-the-perfect-temperature-no-ac-required/">Wristify, a wristband that could make air conditioning obsolete</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>Being prototyped at MIT, <a href="http://wristifyme.com/">Writify</a>, is trying to provide 
 temperature control (the function of a thermostat) by deceiving our senses.</li>
      <li>It tries to exploit the idea that cooling or heating only a part of the
 body makes us think differently about how cold or hot we are. </li>
      <li>Not only can it make AC’s obsolete, but also allow personalized, dynamic
 climate control. So, two people in the same room can enjoy a personalized
 climate. </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><strong><a href="http://www.wired.com/2014/06/google-balloons-year-later">Google’s balloon project, a year later</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>A year ago, Google <a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.in/2013/06/introducing-project-loon.html">announced the Loon project</a>. 
Its aims and ideas can be summarized by 
        <blockquote><p>We believe that it might actually be possible to build a ring of balloons, flying around the globe on the stratospheric winds, that provides Internet access to the earth below.</p></blockquote>
      </li>
      <li>Over the year, they have been able to demonstrate how the plan can succeed.</li>
      <li>While initially, the balloons only lasted only a few days, Google was able
to identify the causes of failure by extensive analysis. </li>
      <li>Small, undetectable leaks in the polymer skins that must withstand huge
atmospheric pressure were identified as the primary cause of failure.</li>
      <li>“The Loon crew not only strengthened the fragile seams where leaks often
occurred but took fanatic care in handling the envelopes.”
        <blockquote><p>Google also improved Loon flight times by dramatically upgrading the altitude control system, increasing the vertical range of the balloons so they can catch more favorable winds. (Its balloons “steer” their way around the world by placing themselves in wind currents headed in the right direction.) As a result, it’s not unusual for Google to keep balloons flying for 75 days. One craft, dubbed Ibis 152 (Google uses bird species to nickname its balloons), has been aloft over 100 daysand is still flying. An earlier balloon, Ibis 162, circled the globe three times before descending. (It completed one circumnavigation in 22 days, a world record.)</p></blockquote>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>Since the balloons had to stay in flight for long, Google couldn’t just rely
 on the data from National Oceanic Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), which
 supplied forecast for only 16 days. Google uses a giant database of weather 
 data to predict weather and wind conditions to be able to plot the optimal
 path (maximize battery life and avoid bad weather).</p>
      </li>
      <li>Loon can now also send data using LTE spectrum.
        <ul>
          <li>This boost the capacity of connections.</li>
          <li>Provides a reason for telecommunication companies to partner with them
to help provide signal in dead spots even in urban areas.</li>
        </ul>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>Google had recently <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/04/14/google-acquires-titan-aerospace-the-drone-company-pursued-by-facebook/">acquired Titan Aerospace</a>,
which makes high-altitude, solar powered drones.</p>
      </li>
      <li>By the next year, they expect to be able to provide service in certain
areas/countries.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><strong><a href="http://blogs.technet.com/b/microsoft_blog/archive/2014/06/16/microsoft-azure-machine-learning-combines-power-of-comprehensive-machine-learning-with-benefits-of-cloud.aspx">Microsoft Azure ML as a service</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>
        <p>Microsoft is using its experience in Machine Learning and its own cloud platform, 
Azure, to provide a platform for building ‘predictive analytics solutions’</p>

        <blockquote><p>Microsoft Azure Machine Learning, a fully-managed cloud service for building predictive analytics solutions, helps overcome the challenges most businesses have in deploying and using machine learning. How? By delivering a comprehensive machine learning service that has all the benefits of the cloud. In mere hours, with Azure ML, customers and partners can build data-driven applications to predict, forecast and change future outcomes – a process that previously took weeks and months.</p></blockquote>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><strong><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/16/box-acquires-yc-backed-streem/">Box acquires Streem</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>Streem is a company that allows customers to stream files to their desktops.</li>
      <li>From the description, it appears that the streaming experience was as if the file was present locally.</li>
      <li>It had <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/04/25/streem-seed-funding/">raised $875m in funding
recently</a> and was
backed by <a href="http://www.ycombinator.com/">YCombinator</a> </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ol>

<p> 
 </p>

<hr />
<p><em>‘Tech News’ is a series of articles where I attempt to share and summarize
recent developments in technology (and the related industry) that interest,
amaze and/or excite me. These would attempt to cover topics ranging from impressive 
apps to Google’s latest acquisition to jaw-dropping updates from SpaceX or Tesla Motors
and much more.</em></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Evernote OAuth in C++]]></title>
    <link href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/05/11/evernote-oauth-in-c-plus-plus/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-11T19:14:33+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/05/11/evernote-oauth-in-c-plus-plus</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Due to the lack of an official <a href="https://evernote.com">Evernote</a> client for
Linux and dissatisfied with solutions like
<a href="https://github.com/nvbn/everpad">Neverpad</a> and <a href="http://sourceforge.net/projects/nevernote/">NixNote (formerly
Nevernote)</a>, I have started working
on <a href="https://github.com/rajatkhanduja/Evernote-for-linux">my own Linux client</a>.</p>

<p>It was while developing this that I learned that <a href="https://github.com/evernote/evernote-sdk-cpp">Evernote SDK for
C++</a> doesn’t really provide any
integration with OAuth. I couldn’t even find a well formed solution for the
same on the Internet, except some forum posts suggesting using any available
OAuth 1.0 client. Searching for OAuth clients for C++, I found
<a href="https://github.com/pipacs/o2">O2</a>.  Using this, I was able to create a simple
OAuth integration for Evernote. </p>

<p>Here are the steps :-</p>

<!--more-->

<ol>
  <li>Taking cue from <a href="https://github.com/pipacs/o2/blob/master/src/o1dropbox.h">O2 integration with Dropbox</a>, 
I extended O1 to create <code>EvernoteAuthenticator</code></li>
</ol>

<script src="https://gist.github.com/rajatkhanduja/edbb7f8d162912b38157.js?file=EvernoteAuthenticator.h"></script>

<ol>
  <li><code>EvernoteClient</code> demonstrates how <code>EvernoteAuthenticator</code> is initialized and called.
 Moreover, it handles the signals generated by <code>EvernoteAuthenticator</code> to open
 a browser, which is required for the user to enter his credentials to log in.
 It also allows the developer to use the sandboxed environment (more about that later).</li>
</ol>

<script src="https://gist.github.com/rajatkhanduja/edbb7f8d162912b38157.js?file=EvernoteClient.h"></script>

<script src="https://gist.github.com/rajatkhanduja/edbb7f8d162912b38157.js?file=EvernoteClient.cpp"></script>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Docspad SDK]]></title>
    <link href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/05/01/docspad-sdk/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-01T16:46:51+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/05/01/docspad-sdk</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In an <a href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/03/12/hasjob-plus-docspad/">earlier post</a>, I had
discussed how I integrated <a href="http://docspad.com">Docspad API</a> with
<a href="http://hasjob.co">Hasjob</a>.  As there was no Docspad SDK at that time, its
absence made me realize their importance. Having to deal with raw API calls,
these were the primary problems that I faced, which I thought could be resolved
by a Software Development Kit (SDK) :-</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p><strong>API lets me talk to your tool, but not in my language</strong></p>

    <p>Say I am developing in Python and I have a dictionary of parameters explaining 
 all that I need the API to do, but the API doesn’t understand the dictionary!
 I would need to convert all those parameters and variables in GET/POST variables
 that before I can get the task done. Moreover, the conventions in your API
 might be extremely different from those of my project, making things worse.</p>

    <p>Certainly, I could work around that by wrapping around your API, which brings
 me to the next point.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Managing network calls and errors is annoying</strong></p>

    <p>There are API errors and then there are network/connection errors, timeouts
 and what not. The last thing I need when dealing with a project idea is to
 get stuck understanding what an error code means. SDKs not only help translate
 the content in the developer’s language, but also the errors. An exception
 that describes the error makes it easy for the developer to handle
 certain edge cases without the program blowing up in the users’ face.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>SDKs provide code samples</strong></p>

    <p>Even if a developer doesn’t need the entire SDK, either because he only
 requires to make a few calls to the API or he/she does not think the SDK
 interacts well with his tool, an openly available SDK still provides code
 samples to the developer to help him/her manage basic things. Be it managing
 errors or creating request URLs, SDKs can act as a good demonstration of how
 the APIs must be used.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/sniketh">Niketh</a> had already been planning to release SDKs
himself, so when I suggested it to him, he was eager to get started! Soon
<!--more-->
after, I began working on a Python SDK as I already had written some <a href="https://github.com/rajatkhanduja/hasjob/commit/45945f1cbad17dbc03839388a05cacb0bbf3d07b">code to
wrap around Docspad API while integrating with
Hasjob</a>.
For inspiration and ideas about how a SDK should be structured, I looked at
other popular SDKs, especially the <a href="https://www.dropbox.com/developers/core/sdks/python">Dropbox
SDKs</a>. </p>

<p>Once we had worked out the design and structure of the <a href="https://github.com/bookpad/docspad-sdk-python">Python
SDK</a>, we aimed to keep other SDKs
quite similar so as to have a common interface throughout languages. However, as 
different languaes have different programming idioms and conventions, having 
the <em>exact same</em> interface across languages would beat the purpose by forcing
the developers to think in terms of another language. As a result, while the
basic ideas and interface remains similar across languages, there are minor 
differences.</p>

<p>With <a href="https://twitter.com/ajayn1609">Ajay’s</a> help, we have been able to release
an entire <a href="https://github.com/Bookpad/?query=docspad-sdk">arsenal of SDKs</a> for
<a href="https://github.com/bookpad/docspad-sdk-php">PHP</a>,
<a href="https://github.com/bookpad/docspad-sdk-java">Java</a> and
<a href="https://github.com/bookpad/docspad-sdk-ruby">Ruby</a> developers as well.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en"><p>For all the PHP developers out there, we have officially released our PHP SDK, Happy Hacking <a href="https://t.co/BHvmu7623g">https://t.co/BHvmu7623g</a> !!</p>&mdash; Bookpad Inc (@bookpadinc) <a href="https://twitter.com/bookpadinc/statuses/450967924216692736">April 1, 2014</a></blockquote>
<script async="" src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>So how do our SDKs solve the problems discussed in the beginning? Using the
Ruby SDK, for instance, this is how one could write a program to upload a
document, create a new session, get a view url and then delete the document.</p>

<div class="bogus-wrapper"><notextile><figure class="code"><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class="line-number">1</span>
<span class="line-number">2</span>
<span class="line-number">3</span>
<span class="line-number">4</span>
<span class="line-number">5</span>
<span class="line-number">6</span>
<span class="line-number">7</span>
<span class="line-number">8</span>
<span class="line-number">9</span>
<span class="line-number">10</span>
<span class="line-number">11</span>
<span class="line-number">12</span>
<span class="line-number">13</span>
<span class="line-number">14</span>
<span class="line-number">15</span>
<span class="line-number">16</span>
<span class="line-number">17</span>
<span class="line-number">18</span>
</pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="ruby"><span class="line"><span class="nb">load</span> <span class="s1">&#39;docspad.rb&#39;</span>
</span><span class="line">
</span><span class="line"><span class="k">begin</span>
</span><span class="line">    <span class="n">client</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="no">DocspadClient</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">new</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="no">YOUR_API_KEY</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class="line">    <span class="n">doc</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="n">client</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">upload</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="no">PATH_TO_FILE</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="c1"># Uploads file; returns an instance of DocspadDocument</span>
</span><span class="line">    <span class="k">begin</span>
</span><span class="line">        <span class="n">status</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="n">doc</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">getStatus</span>
</span><span class="line">        <span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="n">status</span>
</span><span class="line">        <span class="nb">sleep</span> <span class="p">(</span><span class="mi">1</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class="line">    <span class="k">end</span> <span class="k">until</span> <span class="n">status</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">conversionStatus</span> <span class="o">==</span> <span class="ss">DocspadDocument</span><span class="p">:</span><span class="ss">:ConversionStatus</span><span class="o">::</span><span class="no">COMPLETED</span>
</span><span class="line">
</span><span class="line">    <span class="n">session</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="n">doc</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">newSession</span>
</span><span class="line">    <span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="n">doc</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">getViewUrl</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">session</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class="line">    <span class="n">doc</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">deleteSession</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">session</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class="line">    <span class="n">doc</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">delete</span>
</span><span class="line"><span class="k">rescue</span> <span class="no">DocspadError</span> <span class="o">=&gt;</span> <span class="n">error</span>
</span><span class="line">    <span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="n">error</span>
</span><span class="line"><span class="k">end</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div>

<p>Note how not only the developer doesn’t need to care about the details of the
network call, such as URL and the POST parameters, he is also freed of the hassle
of checking and managing all the errors that could arise. Moreover, with little
documentation available with the methods, a developer can get started
integrating the API into his project, without going through the entire <a href="http://bookpad.in/developer/gettingstarted">API
documentation</a> and preparing
himself for all kinds of response the API could return.</p>

<p>So, what are you waiting for? Get yourself an <a href="http://docspad.com/signup/freetrial">API
key</a> now and jump start your Docspad
integration with the SDKs. For issues or bugs with the SDKs, you could use the
issue tracker on Github or reach out to Docspad
(<a href="https://twitter.com/docspadofficial">@docspadofficial</a>) on Twitter [or just
drop by and say Hi]. If you are looking for SDK for some other language or have something to say about the post, leave a comment below.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Augmenting HasJob with Docspad]]></title>
    <link href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/03/12/hasjob-plus-docspad/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-12T00:06:09+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/03/12/hasjob-plus-docspad</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>About two months ago, <a href="http://twitter.com/sniketh">Niketh</a> came up with an idea
to augment the job application process on <a href="https://hasjob.co">Hasjob</a>.  Having
made the quite awesome product, <a href="http://docspad.com">Docspad</a> for handling
documents in web applications, he certainly noticed the lack of the option to
let a job applicant upload a CV while applying through Hasjob. While the user
could add details about himself/herself in a text field, nothing tells as much
about an applicant as a personalized CV. As the <a href="https://github.com/hasgeek/hasjob">code for the website is open
sourced</a> and written in Python, I took this
opportunity to check out the <a href="http://docspad.com/documentation/gettingstarted">Docspad
APIs</a> and spend a weekend
contributing to a Python based open source project! </p>

<p>But before I dive into the task and the experience, let’s first discuss more about 
Hasjob and Docspad.</p>

<p>Hasjob is <a href="http://hasgeek.com">HasGeek</a>’s job board. Hasgeek, based out of
Bangalore, is known for organizing technology events for geeks and developers
in India. Some of these events include Hackathons and
<a href="https://hacknight.in">Hacknights</a>, which are loved among the geeks. HasGeek
lives up to its name by providing the source code to their website and its
components under open source licenses on <a href="https://github.com/hasgeek/">Github</a>.</p>

<p>With the goal of making digital content more accessible, Niketh and
<a href="https://twitter.com/bandiaditya">Aditya</a> founded <a href="http://bookpad.in">Bookpad</a>
(<a href="http://twitter.com/bookpadinc">@bookpadinc</a>). <a href="http://docspad.com">Docspad</a> is
their first product, which provides an easy solution for developers to make
applications with document handling capabilities. The set of APIs make it easy
for a developer to provide users with the option to upload and view documents
through the web browser on any device ranging from mobile to desktop.
<!--more--></p>

<p>Now, the primary task was to provide a job applicant with the option to upload
a document as his CV and allow the employer to view the same. Moreover, we
wanted the integration to make as little changes to the current workflow and
code architecture.  The reason behind this was two-fold : </p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>allow seamless transition to the new workflow.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>avoid making changes to the database layer or code architecture to make it
easy to integrate and make it live at the earliest.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>As a result, we settled on providing the user the option to upload a PDF, DOC
or a DOCX file while filling up the rest of the application. To avoid making
changes to the database layer, this document is only temporarily stored on the
HasJob server until it is uploaded to Docspad.  Thereafter, a URL based on the
<code>docid</code> returned by Docspad Upload API is simply attached to the
<code>apply_message</code> field, which is the one that the employer receives in an email
allowing the employer to view the document with or without downloading it to
his device. The Docspad HTML5 based viewer can be embeded right into the
application, allowing us to let the user view the uploaded content from within
Hasjob’s website. </p>

<p>This process is quite simple to code, made simpler by the quite flexible 
<a href="http://flask.pocoo.org">Flask microframework</a> used for the Hasjob site along
with the easy Docspad API.</p>

<p>Some highlights of the project were :- </p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Wrapping around Docspad API</strong></p>

    <p>Since Docspad didn’t have any publicly available SDKs at the time, I began
by building a wrapper around the APIs. <a href="https://github.com/rajatkhanduja/hasjob/commit/45945f1cbad17dbc03839388a05cacb0bbf3d07b">This code</a>
later became the boilerplate for a <a href="https://github.com/Bookpad/docspad-sdk-python">Python SDK for Docspad</a>,
which will soon be stable. SDKs for several other languages and platforms
are in the pipeline too. SDKs not only make it easier to build applications
on, but also provide sample code for using the APIs for those who like to
build their own tools.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Lastuser and HasGeek Auth</strong></p>

    <p>HasGeek uses <a href="http://auth.hasgeek.com">HasGeek Auth</a> for authorization and
user management for its sites. It is powered by <a href="https://github.com/hasgeek/lastuser">Lastuser</a>,
which has been developed by HasGeek themselves! At that time, I was still 
getting to know more about HasGeek’s open sourced components and was quite
impressed with their dedication to sharing all these tools that they had
developed. </p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>In the end, it turned out to be a great weekend project and let me get
acquainted with Flask and Docspad API. Now, every time I encounter a site that
doesn’t provide good support for uploading/viewing documents, I wonder all the
things they could do with the API! In fact, there are several other job portals
that could make use of the API in quite the same way. </p>

<p>While I didn’t follow up much after sending them the
<a href="https://github.com/hasgeek/hasjob/pull/81">pull request</a>, Niketh has been in
touch with them and informs me that they are quite pleased with the
implementation. Eagerly awaiting for the integration to go live! </p>

<p>Do leave your suggestions, about the blog or the project, in the comments below.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Octopress?]]></title>
    <link href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/03/11/all-set-and-ready-to-go/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-11T23:00:37+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/03/11/all-set-and-ready-to-go</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Finally, the site is up and ready! Now, all that remains is for me to make all 
this effort worthwhile and start blogging regularly. </p>

<p>The experience of setting up this blog, however, taught me a lot of things. Not 
just the lessons required to setup <a href="http://octopress.org">Octopress</a> or this
particular theme (<a href="https://github.com/shashankmehta/greyshade/">Greyshade</a>) or 
the DNS, but …. oh, who am I kidding, that’s the set of things I gained out of 
this entire experience. But they are not really worth sharing, except probably
the incident where I ended up with an infinite loop of URL redirection because
of an error in configuring the DNS! </p>

<p>So, this post will be less about the hows, but whys! Why did I choose Octopress
(and Greyshade) and why do I expect this to be a good choice? That’s the question
I will focus on. </p>

<!--more-->

<ol>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Blogging right from my editor</strong></p>

    <p>While this might not make much sense to a lot of people, it means a lot to 
some of us to be able to do most of the things from within our favorite editor.
Being a <a href="http://vim.org">vim</a> fan myself, it gives me immense pleasure to be 
able to write this blog from the editor. The fools who’d argue that one could
just copy the content from one’s editor for blogging doesn’t know the importance
of formatting, hyperlinking, etc. in blogging. It becomes all the more important
when you aim to write blogs that would tend to include code snippets. Like
Latex, I could write most of the content first and worry about the
formatting later. That brings me to the next point …</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Not having to worry about formatting</strong></p>

    <p>I quite perfectly fit the stereotype of developers who lack any sense about
the UI/UX. Many a times <a href="http://vickychijwani.github.io">Vicky</a> has laughed
off at the interface I found ‘usable’. In such a case, it only makes it harder
for me to imagine how the out put of my blog should look like. What Octopress
(or most such tools) offer, like Latex, is that most of the formatting 
decisions are taken care of without asking me. For instance, I needn’t worry
about the size of the heading or the color of the &lt;a&gt; tags. Should
it look green on hover or yellow? I needn’t worry about that. While at the same 
time, I get the ability to tinker parts that I do need fixed or changed. This
might be probably a good example of 
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Paradox_of_Choice%3A_Why_More_Is_Less">Paradox of Choice</a>. 
 I don’t have to think about making responsive UI, or the alignment of text
 or the margin-width, which saves me from making a lot of decisions and I 
 feel less tense! </p>

    <p>Having tried some platforms prior to this, I know that most platforms don’t
offer smooth writing/formatting tools. My experience with 
<a href="http://blogger.com">Blogger</a> was quite troublesome when I kept running into
issues with the blockquote tag and had to resolve it by looking into the
HTML itself. <a href="http://wordpress.org">Wordpress</a> and <a href="http://medium.com">Medium</a>
seemed to provide great formatting tools for general blogging, but none
that had good support for technical blogs right out of the box. Sure, there 
are plugins and being a geek I could have found them, but it only convinces
me that they were not made for technical content.</p>

    <p>Moreover, being a vim fan, I enjoy tools that focus on commands/instructions
based on ‘typed commands’ rather than key combinations. vim’s support
for markdown only makes it easier for me to be sure of getting what I expect.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Writing in offline mode</strong></p>

    <p>While this might be more of a perk that I expect to use over time, this is 
barely something I have required as of now. Since the setup doesn’t require
a special server to interpret the content, I can preview and/or save a draft
whenever I want. Only to deploy do I need access to the Internet. However,
as I am connected most of the time, this might not be as useful.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>Anyway, this is me just getting started with this platform and resuming blogging
after a long time. Maybe I’d have a lot of changes to these initial thoughts,
maybe not.</p>

<p>Cheers!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Migrating to Octopress]]></title>
    <link href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/03/10/migrating-to-octopress/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-10T07:51:16+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/03/10/migrating-to-octopress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Now that I have a domain of my own and <a href="http://pages.github.com/">Github Pages</a>
are a good way to write and maintain a blog, I am trying to make a shift to
Octopress based blogging. While I maintain (if 8-13 months of inactivity counts
as maintaining) two blogs, <a href="http://blog.rajatkhanduja.com">Outlet</a> and 
<a href="http://techblog.rajatkhanduja.com">Technical Outlet</a>, I would be dropping the 
latter and shifting here. </p>

<p>At the time of writing this article, I do have certain projects that I would
like to write about. 
<!--more--></p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Integrating <a href="http://docspad.com">Docspad</a> with <a href="http://hasjob.co">HasJob</a></strong> </p>

    <p>More on this soon. Meanwhile, here’s the 
 <a href="https://github.com/hasgeek/hasjob/pull/81">pull request</a> for the same.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong><a href="https://github.com/Bookpad/docspad-sdk-python">Docspad Python SDK</a></strong> </p>

    <p>While working on the <a href="https://github.com/hasgeek/hasjob">HasJob code</a>, the
 need for such SDKs (more will follow) became clear. </p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong><a href="https://github.com/rajatkhanduja/WebComics">Android based Webcomics Reader</a></strong> </p>

    <p>As an avid Webcomics fan (my favorites being <a href="http://xkcd.com">XKCD</a> and
 <a href="http://smbc-comics.com">SMBC</a>, my first attempt at making an Android
 application revolves around the idea of making a single app for my favorite
 webcomics.  </p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong><a href="https://github.com/rajatkhanduja/ZeroKnowledgeDocuments/">Zero Knowledge Documents</a></strong></p>

    <p>While I have not made any improvements up on the basic tool in a long time,
 it has served my purpose well enough for now. </p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>But more on these topics later for now I have to go through the painful process
of setting up a blog. No offence to any of the developers or contributors of 
Octopress, but any such setup is painful, only the magnitude varies. It has
certainly been easy so far to get up and running, but there are several things
I’d want on the site. Let’s see how that goes about. Maybe, this could be the
subject of yet another post. </p>

<p>Here’s hoping for a better blogging future. </p>

<p>Cheers!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
