<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: ycombinator | sudo random]]></title>
  <link href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/categories/ycombinator/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-07-15T11:48:16+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://rajatkhanduja.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Rajat Khanduja]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tech News: Bitstamped, ClearTax, OnionShare,...]]></title>
    <link href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/30/tech-news-bitstamped-cleartax-onionshare/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-30T02:07:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/30/tech-news-bitstamped-cleartax-onionshare</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ol>
  <li><a href="/techblog/2014/06/30/tech-news-bitstamped-cleartax-onionshare/#bitstamped">Bitstamped</a></li>
  <li><a href="/techblog/2014/06/30/tech-news-bitstamped-cleartax-onionshare/#atap">Project Ara and Tango updates at Google I/O</a></li>
  <li><a href="/techblog/2014/06/30/tech-news-bitstamped-cleartax-onionshare/#spy-phone">Security Researchers Uncover The Tools Governments Use To Spy On Our Phones</a></li>
  <li><a href="/techblog/2014/06/30/tech-news-bitstamped-cleartax-onionshare/#chromecast-ultrasound">How Can Chromecast Connect To Your Friend’s Phones Without Using WiFi? Ultrasonic Sounds</a></li>
  <li><a href="/techblog/2014/06/30/tech-news-bitstamped-cleartax-onionshare/#onionshare">Onionshare : A tool to share files securely and anonymously</a></li>
  <li><a href="/techblog/2014/06/30/tech-news-bitstamped-cleartax-onionshare/#cleartax">YC-backed ClearTax tackles Indian’s fast growing online tax filing market</a></li>
  <li><a href="/techblog/2014/06/30/tech-news-bitstamped-cleartax-onionshare/#grasswire">Grasswire – an Internet newsroom curated and fact-checked by everyone</a></li>
  <li><a href="/techblog/2014/06/30/tech-news-bitstamped-cleartax-onionshare/#yo-hackathon">Yo! Hackathon Attempts To Show How Yo Can Grow</a></li>
</ol>

<!--more-->

<p>External links:</p>

<ol>
  <li><a href="https://github.com/microg">Micro-g Project</a> : Aims to provide a free, fully compatible replacement of the often used proprietary GAPPS package by Google.</li>
  <li><a href="http://www.nomachetejuggling.com/2014/06/24/the-worst-programming-interview-question/">The worst programming interview
question</a>:
An article on why questions like ‘Write a function that can detect a cycle in a
linked list’ are inappropriate for an interview.</li>
  <li><a href="http://www.theverge.com/2014/6/27/5849272/material-world-how-google-discovered-what-software-is-made-of">Material world: how Google discovered what software is made of</a></li>
</ol>

<p> 
 </p>

<hr />

<ol>
  <li><a name="bitstamped"></a><strong><a href="https://bitstamped.io/">Bitstamped</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>Provides a publicly verifiable timestamp that can be added to printed
documents using a QR code.</li>
      <li>
        <p>It can be used to show that someone came up with an idea first.</p>

        <p><img src="http://www.inkfactory.com/bitstamped.io/zuck.gif"></p>

        <p><blockquote><p>We don’t know if it’ll stand up in court, but for informal mediation of disputes, this might be useful.</p></blockquote></p>
      </li>
      <li>This is an application of the Bitcoin protocol to establish ‘ownership’.</li>
      <li>The uploaded file is used to create a SHA256 digest, which is then
stored in blockchain, Bitcoin-protocol’s way of storing some information
forever in a shared manner.</li>
      <li>
        <p>Bitstamp uses <a href="http://www.proofofexistence.com/">Proof of Existence</a>
<a href="http://www.proofofexistence.com/developers">API</a> to create a service
for the less technically inclined.</p>

        <p><blockquote><p>We didn’t invent timestamping checksums on the Blockchain; our objective is to provide an easy to use interface to complete that task and provide a service for users to print a verifiable timestamp on their documents.</p></blockquote></p>
      </li>
      <li>The file could either be shared or kept private (or shared at a later 
point). The file is stored on Amazon S3 storage service.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="atap"></a><strong><a href="http://mashable.com/2014/06/26/google-project-tango-ara/">Project Ara and Tango updates at Google I/O</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>Google’s <a href="http://google.com/atap">Advanced Technology and Projects lab</a>
provided some interesting updates to <a href="http://projectara.com">Project Ara</a>
and <a href="https://www.google.com/atap/projecttango/#project">Project Tango</a></li>
      <li>Project Ara, that began as a concept called (and propogated by) <a href="https://phonebloks.com">PhoneBloks</a> aiming to create a smartphone with modular units
allowing for increased customization and longer life of phones.</li>
      <li>At Google I/O, <a href="http://mashable.com/2014/06/26/google-project-ara-prototype/">a prototype of a phone by Project Ara was unveiled</a>
<blockquote><p>When Eremenko brought the prototype on stage during a breakout session of Google I/O at San Francisco’s Moscone Center and flashed the Android bootup screen, the audience went wild. Ultimately, the phone failed to fully load (though the crowd cheered anyway), and Eremenko said plenty of challenges lie ahead for Ara, including the challenge of building the tech into a beautiful design for consumers.</p></blockquote></li>
      <li>Project Tango aims to give mobile devices a human-scale understanding
of space and motion</li>
      <li>
        <p>At Google I/O, </p>

        <p><blockquote><p>Project Tango head Johnny Lee started off the session with an onstage demo, showing off the technology that uses multiple cameras to create 3D renderings by weaving together depth and location information. <br/>…<br/>Lee showed off the tablet, which was also on display for passerby throughout the conference. He received a hearty round of applause when he generated a 3D replica of the stage in real time using Tango’s depth cameras. He also demonstrated a few games on the device, and at one point crouched to his knees to interact with a small virtual wizard on the screen.</p></blockquote></p>
      </li>
      <li>Developers will be able to buy the tablet and build apps on it by
later this year.</li>
    </ul>

    <iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/cV8JDSO1NS8" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
  </li>
  <li><a name="spy-phone"></a><strong><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/25/security-researchers-uncover-the-tools-governments-use-to-spy-on-our-phones/">Security Researchers Uncover The Tools Governments Use To Spy On Our Phones</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>Researchers from
<a href="http://www.securelist.com/en/blog/8231/HackingTeam_2_0_The_Story_Goes_Mobile">Kaspersky</a>
and <a href="https://citizenlab.org/2014/06/backdoor-hacking-teams-tradecraft-android-implant/">Citizen
Lab</a> published research on a new type of malware designed to
give police complete access to a suspect’s phone.</li>
      <li>
        <p><a href="http://www.hackingteam.com/index.php/remote-control-system">Remote Control System (RCS)/Galileo</a> allows for full control of the data on the phone 
and allows listeners/police to activate the microphone on Android, iOS
and Blackberry devices.</p>

        <p><blockquote><p>The major exploits included access to the following phone features and apps:<br/>Control of Wi-Fi, GPS, GPRS<br/>Recording voice<br/>E-mail, SMS, MMS<br/>Listing files<br/>Cookies<br/>Visited URLs<br/>Cached web pages<br/>Address book<br/>Call history<br/>Notes<br/>Calendar<br/>Clipboard<br/>List of apps<br/>SIM change<br/>Live microphone<br/>Camera shots<br/>Support chats, WhatsApp, Skype, Viber<br/>Log keystrokes from all apps and screens via libinjection</p></p><p>        <p></p></blockquote></p>
      </li>
      <li>Installing it on iOS requires a jailbroken phone, however it can be 
installed on Android without any root privileges. </li>
      <li>The app was made by a Milan-based company, <a href="http://www.hackingteam.com/">Hacking Team</a>
that has made a niche for itself selling surveillance software to 
police in several countries.</li>
      <li>
        <p>While its <a href="http://www.theverge.com/2014/6/24/5837660/new-spy-tool-lets-cops-bug-your-phone-remotely">still unclear where RCS is currently used</a>
but researchers identified a piece of RCS software in a trojan horse
that appears like an Arabic news reader, making a fake ‘Qatif’ news app
used in Saudi Arabia.</p>

        <p><blockquote><p>Hacking Team says it won’t sell its products to governments that are blacklisted by NATO, but critics say the company’s tools have already been used against pro-democracy Moroccan journalists and at least one American citizen.</p></blockquote></p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>Edward Snowden had pointed out that government had methods to 
remotely hack a user’s phone and spy on the user.</p>

        <iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/8GhEvuU8LjU" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="chromecast-ultrasound"></a><strong><a href="techcrunch.com/2014/06/26/how-can-chromecast-connect-to-your-friends-phones-without-using-wifi-ultrasonic-sounds/">How Can Chromecast Connect To Your Friend’s Phones Without Using WiFi? Ultrasonic Sounds</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>In Google I/O, it was announced that <a href="/techblog/2014/06/26/tech-news-google-io-keynote/#chromecast">Chromecast would allow anyone in
the same room to share the screen without requiring them to be on the
same wifi. </a> </li>
      <li>In a post keynote presentation, it was cleared up that this was achieved
using Ultrasonic soundwaves. </li>
      <li>Once configured, Chromecast will push uniquely generated ultrasonic
waves through the TV’s speakers encoding information required by the
phone to pair up.</li>
      <li>Apps using Chromecast SDK will listen for these ultrasounds (relying on
the phone’s microphone) to detect and show the option to pair up
with Chromecast.</li>
      <li>Earlier this year, <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/02/16/google-acquires-slicklogin-the-sound-based-password-alternative/">Google had acquired SlickLogin</a>, 
which used ultrasonic soundwaves to provide something like a 2-factor
authentication.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="onionshare"></a><strong><a href="https://onionshare.org/">Onionshare : A tool to share files securely and anonymously</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>
        <p><a href="https://github.com/micahflee/onionshare/blob/master/README.md">How does it work?</a></p>

        <p><blockquote><p>OnionShare lets you securely and anonymously share a file of any size with someone. It works by starting a web server, making it accessible as a Tor hidden service, and generating an unguessable URL to access and download the file. It doesn’t require setting up a server on the internet somewhere or using a third party filesharing service. You host the file on your own computer and use a Tor hidden service to make it temporarily accessible over the internet. The other user just needs to use Tor Browser to download the file from you.</p></blockquote></p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>If the file being sent is secret, one would want to use a secret
way to send over the aforementioned URL and <a href="https://pressfreedomfoundation.org/encryption-works#otr">Off-the-Record encrypted
chat</a> is
recommended for that.</p>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="cleartax"></a><strong><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/24/yc-backed-cleartax-tackles-indias-fast-growing-online-tax-filing-market/">YC-backed ClearTax tackles Indian’s fast growing online tax filing market</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li><a href="http://cleartax.in/">ClearTax</a>, founded in 2011 and based in Delhi,
already has a strong presence in India automating the income tax filing
process for workers.</li>
      <li>Over 300,00 people used ClearTax last year to file their taxes. </li>
      <li>First company to join YCombinator that focuses on only the Indian market.</li>
      <li>
        <p>It is not a typical <a href="http://ycombinator.com/">Y Combinator</a> launch</p>

        <p><blockquote><p>While their market opportunity is currently in India, ClearTax decided to join Y Combinator because the startup got access to “a set of resources we don’t get in India,” says founder Archit Gupta.</p></p><p>        <p>“We were missing some of the mentorship in India for example. I worked in Silicon Valley before. I was an engineer at Data Domain, which was acquired by EMC. So I had seen how being in the Valley is super useful, so that whole thing made it very, very clear to us that we should come out here.”</p></blockquote></p>
      </li>
      <li>Two of the cofounders, Anupam Mediratta and Archit Gupta, <a href="http://yourstory.com//2012/06/file-tax-online-cleartax/">graduated from
IIT Guwahati</a>,
while the third, RR Gupta, is a CA by profession with decades of
experience in taxation and accounting</li>
      <li>There are several companies in India that offer online tax services.</li>
      <li>
        <p>ClearTax, however, <a href="http://cleartax.in/Meta/Pricing">follows a freemium
model</a> where <a href="http://www.nextbigwhat.com/file-tax-returns-online-for-free-cleartax-297/">they can file their taxes
for free but pay to consult tax experts to get help on saving and
filing</a>.</p>

        <p><blockquote><p>To use ClearTax, all someone needs to do is upload the form onto the website. Then ClearTax’s software automatically pulls out relevant data, so users don’t have to manually key in any numbers or information, and prepares tax forms for each user, a process the startup says can take as little as 15 minutes.<br/>Gupta says ClearTax’s main competitor is the government, which has its own online filing software, but that’s complicated to use, especially since people need to figure out which one out of seven tax forms they need to fill out</p></blockquote></p>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="grasswire"></a><strong><a href="http://grasswire.com">Grasswire – an Internet newsroom curated and fact-checked by everyone</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>Grasswire is a social news aggregator.</li>
      <li>It provides a live twitter feed on the topic along with other sources
of news.</li>
      <li>Users can ‘confirm’ or ‘refute’ news or information by linking to a 
source</li>
      <li>The website seems to be in early stages.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="yo-hackathon"></a><strong><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/28/yo-hackathon-attempts-to-show-how-yo-can-grow/">Yo! Hackathon Attempts To Show How Yo Can Grow</a></strong> 
    <ul>
      <li><a href="http://www.justyo.co/">Yo!</a> made a lot of news recently when it received 
$1.2m in funding based on this app that sends across only a two letter
word, ‘Yo!’.</li>
      <li>The two-and-half hour hackathon was an attempt to prove that Yo could 
do much more than just send ‘Yo’ across to friends.</li>
      <li>Using <a href="http://yoapi.justyo.co/">its API</a>, people tried to create several
apps. </li>
      <li>Apps developed during the hackathon :-
        <ul>
          <li><a href="http://www.yoserverisdown.com/">YoServerIsDown</a> allows users to sign
up for this service which will send a ‘Yo’ whenever their server is
down. </li>
          <li><a href="https://twitter.com/Noah_L/status/482731097940193280">YOaster</a> sends
a ‘Yo’ when the toaster has finished toasting the bread.</li>
          <li>Yo Radio bookmarks songs playing on the radio so a user can access information about the song later from a computer</li>
        </ul>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>As we can see from the above ideas, <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/18/yo-yo/">‘Yo’ can meaning
anything</a>.</p>

        <p><blockquote><p>Venture investor (and husband of one of the world’s best-dressed billionaires) Marc Andreessen calls yo an example of one-bit communication – a message that only exists as itself. There is no meaning — the medium is, in fact, the message.</p></blockquote></p>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ol>

<p> 
 </p>

<hr />
<p><em>‘<a href="/techblog/categories/tech-news">Tech News</a>’ is a series of articles where I attempt to share and summarize
recent developments in technology (and the related industry) that interest,
amaze and/or excite me. These would attempt to cover topics ranging from impressive 
apps to Google’s latest acquisition to jaw-dropping updates from SpaceX or Tesla Motors
and much more.</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
