<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: amazon-zocalo | sudo random]]></title>
  <link href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/categories/amazon-zocalo/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-07-15T11:46:08+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://rajatkhanduja.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Rajat Khanduja]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tech News: Self Tracking, MindRDR, Streamfully, ...]]></title>
    <link href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/07/15/tech-news-self-tracking-streamfully-d-programming-lang/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-15T11:03:10+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/07/15/tech-news-self-tracking-streamfully-d-programming-lang</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ol>
  <li><a href="/techblog/2014/07/15/tech-news-self-tracking-streamfully-d-programming-lang/#d-lang">The Next Big Programming Language you’ve never heard</a></li>
  <li><a href="/techblog/2014/07/15/tech-news-self-tracking-streamfully-d-programming-lang/#phant">Phant : A place to push your data</a></li>
  <li><a href="/techblog/2014/07/15/tech-news-self-tracking-streamfully-d-programming-lang/#lifetip">LifeTip : A fitness tracking device that doesn’t need skin contact</a></li>
  <li><a href="/techblog/2014/07/15/tech-news-self-tracking-streamfully-d-programming-lang/#zocalo">Amazon Goes After Box, Dropbox And Huddle, Launches Zocalo For Secure Enterprise Storage</a></li>
  <li><a href="/techblog/2014/07/15/tech-news-self-tracking-streamfully-d-programming-lang/#raspberry-pi">Raspberry Pi Microcomputer Gets Beefed Up — Still Only Costs $35</a></li>
  <li><a href="/techblog/2014/07/15/tech-news-self-tracking-streamfully-d-programming-lang/#cv">Linux tool to show progress for cp, rm, dd</a></li>
  <li><a href="/techblog/2014/07/15/tech-news-self-tracking-streamfully-d-programming-lang/#track-everything">I track everything about myself</a></li>
  <li><a href="/techblog/2014/07/15/tech-news-self-tracking-streamfully-d-programming-lang/#MindRDR">MindRDR : A Google Glass App that lets you control it with your thoughts</a></li>
  <li><a href="/techblog/2014/07/15/tech-news-self-tracking-streamfully-d-programming-lang/#streamfully">Streamfully Turns Web Links Into Personalized Content Previews</a></li>
  <li><a href="/techblog/2014/07/15/tech-news-self-tracking-streamfully-d-programming-lang/#winkapp">Wink’s Connected Home Collection Arrives At Home Depot</a></li>
  <li><a href="/techblog/2014/07/15/tech-news-self-tracking-streamfully-d-programming-lang/#tablo">Tablo : A platform for self-publishing community</a></li>
  <li><a href="/techblog/2014/07/15/tech-news-self-tracking-streamfully-d-programming-lang/#freble">Freble: A gadget that lets you hold hands online</a></li>
  <li><a href="/techblog/2014/07/15/tech-news-self-tracking-streamfully-d-programming-lang/#pixotale">Pixotale: A Social Networking App for visual storytelling</a></li>
</ol>

<p>External links :-</p>

<ol>
  <li><a href="http://www.drewdavismedia.com/details.php?pid=1">Too much power for one
man</a> : An article on how
Google and its CEO,Larry Page, practically own the world! </li>
  <li><a href="http://www.john-foreman.com/blog/facebooks-solution-to-big-datas-content-problem-dumber-users"> Facebook’s solution to big data’s “content problem:” dumber
users</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://gist.github.com/rygorous/251b945aef2046ac7cee">What I mean when I say, “I think VR is bad
news”</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://highscalability.com/blog/2014/7/14/bitly-lessons-learned-building-a-distributed-system-that-han.html">Bitly: Lessons Learned Building a Distributed System that Handles 6 Billion
Clicks a
Month</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://genius.cat-v.org/richard-feynman/writtings/letters/problems">What problems to solve: A letter by Richard Feynman to his former
student</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://pixotale.com/story/20953465/#storycontent">Why I cancelled my Oculus Rift and You Should too; Because google cardboard
proved it can do a better work cheaper and
bette</a> </li>
  <li><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/07/09/android-wear-needs-to-be-more-thoughtful-about-bugging-you/">Android Wear needs to be more thoughtful about bugging
you</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/07/14/timberman-is-the-new-flappy-bird/">Timberman is the new Flappy Bird</a></li>
</ol>

<!--more-->

<p> 
 </p>

<hr />

<ol>
  <li>
    <p><a name="d-lang"></a> <strong><a href="http://www.wired.com/2014/07/d-programming-language/">The Next Big Programming Language you’ve never heard
of</a></strong></p>

    <ul>
      <li>D programming language got its name, although it was initially called Mars,
because it was seen as a successor of C++.</li>
      <li>It has been around for over 9 years and, unlike most new languages, has
recently picked up momentum.</li>
      <li>This can be attributed to Facebook deciding to experiment with the language.</li>
      <li>The language tries to bridge the gap between languages like C++ and Python,
i.e. the <em>fast</em> languages and <em>easy</em> languages.</li>
      <li>Andrei Alexandrescu, one of the authors of the language, is a research 
scientist at Facebook where his team is trying to rewrite small parts of the 
company using D. Walter Bright, the other author, is also collaborating 
on this project as an outside contractor.</li>
      <li>
        <p>Other languages that try to bridge the gap between the two kinds of languages
are <a href="https://code.google.com/p/go/">Google’s Go Programming Language</a> 
and <a href="https://developer.apple.com/swift/">Apple’s Swift</a></p>

        <p><blockquote><p>“D is similar to C++, but better,” says Brad Anderson, a longtime C++ programmer from Utah who has been using D as well. “It’s high performance, but it’s expressive. You can get a lot done without very much code.”</p></blockquote></p>
      </li>
      <li>Facebook is working on another language,
<a href="http://www.wired.com/2014/03/facebook-hack/">Hack</a>, which is also trying
to bridge this gap. Hack has been used at Facebook to replace the frontend
PHP code and can be seen as a new version of PHP itself. It allows
developers to use both static and dynamic typing, also called <a href="http://homes.soic.indiana.edu/jsiek/what-is-gradual-typing/">gradual
typing</a></li>
      <li>While Hack currently replaces only the front-end at Facebook, D is being 
experimented for backend processes. However, its authors intend D to be the
language of choice for all kinds of tasks.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><a name="phant"></a> <strong><a href="https://data.sparkfun.com/">Phant : A place to push your data</a></strong></p>

    <ul>
      <li><a href="https://data.sparkfun.com/">data.sparkfun.com</a> powered by <a href="https://github.com/sparkfun/phant">Phant</a>,
provides a place to push your data streams. </li>
      <li>This allows developers to send data from any device to the server which stores
the data (up to 500MB, for free). </li>
      <li>This will help developers and hackers ignore the problems around data storage
and focus on applications that require several datapoints to be stored, shared
and analyzed.</li>
      <li>The idea is aimed at providing a platform to bring ‘Internet of things’ to
reality.</li>
      <li>
        <p>How does it work :</p>

        <p><blockquote><p>We thought data storage should be as easy as string concatenation. First, create a stream and you’ll receive a public url and a private key. Then, using the hardware of your choice (Ethernet shield, RasPi, BBB, Electric Imp, WiFly) simply create a string with the data you want to post.</p></blockquote></p>
      </li>
      <li>The underlying engine, Phant, is open-sourced and can be setup on any box,
giving developers control of their own data and allowing other such
services to pop-up.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><a name="lifetip"></a><strong><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/07/14/the-lifetip-doesnt-need-to-touch-you-to-know-your-heart/">LifeTip : A fitness tracking device that doesn’t need skin contact</a></strong></p>

    <ul>
      <li>
        <p>Unlike wearables like FitBit, LifeTip doesn’t require to be in direct
contact with the skin or body. It hooks into a woman’s bra or a man’s shirt
and reads information like ECG (not just heart rate), calories burned and
steps taken by the user.</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>The device is connected to a phone application using bluetooth, which
receives the data and can be used to provide insights into it.</p>

        <p><blockquote><p>Using capacitive technology, the device is able to measure all of these verticals without ever coming into contact with the skin, saving users from potential allergic reactions</p></blockquote></p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>This project was recently launched on
<a href="https://www.indiegogo.com/projects/lifetip-health-wearable-device-no-skin-contact-ecg-technology">Indiegogo</a>,
which is a platform like Kickstarter.</p>
      </li>
    </ul>

    <iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/WiOK2buntdM" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><a name="zocalo"></a> <strong><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/07/10/amazon-goes-after-box-dropbox-and-hudd.le-launches-zocalo-for-secure-enterprise-storage/">Amazon Goes After Box, Dropbox And Huddle, Launches Zocalo For Secure Enterprise Storage</a></strong></p>

    <ul>
      <li>
        <p>Amazon launched <a href="http://aws.amazon.com/zocalo/">Zocalo</a> which is a ‘fully
managed, secure enterprise storage and sharing service with strong
administrative controls and feedback capabilities that improve user
productivity’.</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>It lets users “store, share, and gather feedback on documents,
spreadsheets, presentations, webpages, images, PDFs, or text files – from
the device of their choice.”</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>By providing this service, Amazon has entered into the competition against
the likes of Box and Dropbox. Although there are several players in this 
segment, Amazon seems to be focusing on problems faced by users in using 
these services.</p>
      </li>
      <li>The focus lies on :-
        <ul>
          <li>Easy sharing</li>
          <li>Any device access</li>
          <li>Available with <a href="http://aws.amazon.com/workspaces/">Amazon WorkSpaces</a></li>
          <li>Simple Feedback</li>
          <li>Central file hub</li>
        </ul>
      </li>
      <li>The pricing is quite aggressive. Moreover, <a href="http://aws.amazon.com/zocalo/pricing/">WorkSpaces customers will get
access to Zocalo for free - including 50 GB of storage per WorkSpaces
user</a></li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><a name="raspberry-pi"></a><strong><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/07/14/raspberry-pi-model-b-plus/">Raspberry Pi Microcomputer Gets Beefed Up — Still Only Costs $35</a></strong></p>

    <ul>
      <li>Raspberry Pi launched a new model called <a href="http://www.raspberrypi.org/introducing-raspberry-pi-model-b-plus/">B+</a>.</li>
      <li>Improvements 
        <ul>
          <li>More USB - 4 instead of 2.</li>
          <li>MicroSD slot replacing the SD card slot.</li>
          <li>Lower power consumption</li>
          <li>Improved audio</li>
        </ul>
      </li>
      <li>The new model is available today.</li>
    </ul>

    <iframe src="//player.vimeo.com/video/100672311" width="500" height="281" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><a name="cv"></a> <strong><a href="https://github.com/Xfennec/cv">Linux tool to show progress for cp, rm, dd, …</a></strong></p>

    <ul>
      <li>
        <p>What is it? </p>

        <p><blockquote><p>This tool can be described as a Tiny Dirty Linux Only C command that looks for coreutils basic commands (cp, mv, dd, tar, gzip/gunzip, cat, …) currently running on your system and displays the percentage of copied data.</p></blockquote></p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>How does it work?</p>

        <p><blockquote><p>It simply scans /proc for interesting commands, and then use fd/ and fdinfo/ directories to find opened files and seek position, and reports status for the biggest file.</p></blockquote></p>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><a name="track-everything"></a> <strong><a href="http://aprilzero.com/">I track everything about myself</a></strong></p>

    <ul>
      <li>
        <p>A website by Anand Sharma, living in San Fransisco, displaying all that he
has tracked about himself.</p>

        <p><blockquote><p>This site tracks where I go and what I do every day. Most of the data comes from various apps on my phone.</p></blockquote></p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>Tracking is done using apps and tools like Moves, Nike Plus, Mapbox,
Github, Foursquare, etc.</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>Things that are tracked :-</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fitness related :
            <ul>
              <li>Heart rate, weight and body fat</li>
              <li>Glucose level, HDL, LDL, Sodium, Iron, Potassium, etc.</li>
              <li>Miles run, calories burned, steps walked, etc.</li>
            </ul>
          </li>
          <li>Locations and countries visited</li>
          <li>Miles traveled</li>
        </ul>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><a name="MindRDR"></a><strong><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/07/09/forget-ok-glass-mindrdr-is-a-new-google-glass-app-that-you-control-with-your-thoughts/">MindRDR : A Google Glass App that lets you control it with your thoughts</a></strong></p>

    <ul>
      <li>
        <p>The app links Google Glass with another head mounted hardware, the Neurosky
EEG biosensor, to create a communication loop</p>

        <p><blockquote><p>The Neurosky biosensor picks up on brainwaves that correlate to your ability to focus. The app then translates these brainwaves into a meter reading that gets superimposed on the camera view in Google Glass. As you “focus” more with your mind, the meter goes up, and the app takes a photograph of what you are seeing in front of you. Focus some more, and the meter goes up again and the photo gets posted to Twitter.</p></blockquote></p>

        <p><img src="http://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2014/07/inuse2.png?w=738"></p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>It was created by a team out of <a href="http://www.thisplace.com/">This Place</a> interactive studio,
which has been working on user interface.</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>Very early stages; clumsy prototype and not yet ready for production.</p>

        <p><blockquote><p>The idea here is that this is a minimum viable product, a first step that can be developed further — for example, to create applications to “train” people to concentrate better, or to play games, maybe to help suggest places to get a coffee when your sensor picks up that you’re tired, or for medical applications, for example for people with mobility problems.</p></p><p>        <p>And potentially, you could build out the basic concept with more, lighter and easier-to-use sensors. This Place says that among those who have taken an interest are Stephen Hawking, the famous physicist who is nearly paralysed because of a progressive motor neuron disease.</p></blockquote></p>

        <iframe src="//player.vimeo.com/video/99915694" width="500" height="281" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
        <p><a href="http://vimeo.com/99915694">MindRDR</a> from <a href="http://vimeo.com/thisplacelondon">This Place Ltd</a> on <a href="https://vimeo.com">Vimeo</a>.</p>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><a name="streamfully"></a> <strong><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/07/03/streamfully-content-previews/">Streamfully Turns Web Links Into Personalized
Content
Previews</a></strong></p>

    <ul>
      <li>
        <p>On installing <a href="http://streamful.ly/">Streamfully</a> <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/streamfully/bemdobilmmplpepafjplfkeaaopppdef">Chrome Extension</a>,
every time the user hovers over a link, she can view a preview of the 
page which would contain snippets and images from the page.</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>The snippets are aimed to be user-specific, based on the content it deems 
relevant to the user. </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>This could help user identify if the page in discussion contains information
she is looking for.</p>

        <p><blockquote><p>Pangaro [the creator] suggested that this moves web pages and articles away from being “giant containers” and makes the reading experience “more conversational” — in other words, more relevant to your interests, less repetitive (since Streamfully will focus on what’s unique about a piece of content and what it hasn’t shown you in other previews), and with more of a “dance and flow.”</p></p><p>        <p>And it necessarily mean it will be shallower experience, either — Pangaro said that by since it has lowered “the bio cost of looking” (i.e., the annoyance of clicking on a page and discovering that it isn’t what you were looking for), Streamfully might actually encourage users to spend more time with content once they know it’s a good fit.</p></blockquote></p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>Chrome extension is free and Pangaro plans to generate revenue through ads
and by offering this as a tool to publishers.</p>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="winkapp"></a><strong><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/07/07/winks-connected-home-collection-arrives-at-home-depot/">Wink’s Connected Home Collection Arrives At Home Depot</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>
        <p><a href="http://www.winkapp.com/">Wink</a> is another player in the home automation
segment.</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>Its app allows the user to control and monitor several home appliances 
through their smartphones (iOS or Android).</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>They have, now, released a list of compatible products which are now available
across several locations in the US.</p>

        <p><blockquote><p>The Wink platform is basically a central hub for devices from manufacturers, including Dropcam, Honeywell, Quirky, Schalge, Kwikset and more, giving users a single app for either iOS or Android from which to customize and control them all.</p></blockquote></p>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><a name="tablo"></a> <strong><a href="http://tablo.io/">Tablo : A platform for self-publishing community</a></strong></p>

    <ul>
      <li>
        <p>Founded by Ashley Davies; raised <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/07/10/publishing-start-up-tablo-raises-400000-seed-round/">$400,000 from Y Combinator partner Kevin
Hale and Paul
Reining</a></p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>Focuses on intuitive and nice interface. Allows users to publish instantly,
like while publishing a blog.</p>

        <p><blockquote><p>“As a blogger I was so used to being able to type something and click a publish button,” said Davies. “I wanted to change this and give emerging authors a place where they can easily create, share, and connect with readers. Publishing a book with Tablo is as easy as publishing a blog and, when you finish writing, you’ll have an established readership.</p></p><p>        <p>The service currently has 10,000 authors from 100 countries. Each author has a social profile on the site and authors can invite readers to follow them as they flesh out their books. The service offers a seamless, non-intrusive interface based around the book editor that allows you to enter text and publish it immediately. Book chapters appear as “posts” in the service and users can read them or subscribe to updates.</p></blockquote></p>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><a name="freble"></a> <strong><a href="http://www.cnet.com/news/frebble-i-wanna-hold-your-weird-robotic-hand/">Freble: A gadget that lets you hold hands online</a></strong></p>

    <ul>
      <li>
        <p>Using haptic technology, Frebles provides the sensation of holding hands.</p>

        <p><blockquote><p>Haptic technology built into the Frebble is designed to imitate the feeling of holding someone’s hand. Two pressure sensors on the front pick up on squeezing while two vibration motors and a “squeeze bar” provide the sensation of squeezing back. The bar is like a little lever that extends against the back of your hand. A package of two Frebbles is going for a $99 pledge.</p></blockquote></p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p><a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/396691740/frebble-hold-hands-online">Project on Kickstarter</a></p>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><a name="pixotale"></a> <strong><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/07/02/former-microsoft-engineers-launch-pixotale-a-social-networking-app-for-visual-storytelling">Pixotale: A Social Networking App for visual storytelling</a></strong></p>

    <ul>
      <li>
        <p><a href="http://pixotale.com/">Pixotale</a> is aimed at sharing longer stories with
friends and family, instead of small status updates.</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>Moreover, it is designed to make it easier to create such long stories on 
mobile phones.</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>Created by former Microsoft engineers.</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>Examples of such stories :- </p>

        <ul>
          <li><a href="http://pixotale.com/story/20953465/#storycontent">Why I cancelled my Oculus Rift and You Should too; Because google cardboard
  proved it can do a better work cheaper and
  bette</a> </li>
          <li><a href="http://pixotale.com/story/19277912/">SeaWorld Orlando</a></li>
          <li><a href="http://pixotale.com/story/48425618/">The Most Bloody Infographic About Dictators</a></li>
        </ul>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ol>

<p> 
 </p>

<hr />
<p><em>‘<a href="/techblog/categories/tech-news">Tech News</a>’ is a series of articles where I attempt to share and summarize
recent developments in technology (and the related industry) that interest,
amaze and/or excite me. These would attempt to cover topics ranging from impressive 
apps to Google’s latest acquisition to jaw-dropping updates from SpaceX or Tesla Motors
and much more.</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
