<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: tech-news, | sudo random]]></title>
  <link href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/categories/tech-news/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-06-19T01:55:24+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://rajatkhanduja.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Rajat Khanduja]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tech News: Amazon announces new phone 'Fire']]></title>
    <link href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/19/tech-news-amazon-announces-new-phone-fire/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-19T00:31:53+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/19/tech-news-amazon-announces-new-phone-fire</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ol>
  <li><strong><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/18/amazon-announces-the-fire-phone/">Amazon announces Fire Phone : First phone with head-tracking tech</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>4.7 inch screen, Quad core 2.2GHz, Adreno 330 graphics, 2GB RAM.</li>
      <li>Runs FireOS, a fork of Android.</li>
      <li><a href="http://www.amazon.com/dp/B00EOE0WKQ">Available on contract with AT&amp;T for two years; starting $199</a></li>
      <li>While the hardware is not exceptional, its ability to track user’s 
head is what makes it different from the rest.
<blockquote><p>This is done through four corner-mounted, front-facing infrared cameras and produces wild 3D effects. But it’s not tradition 3D in the sense that images pop out the screen. The head tracking tech adds depth to the phone. It’s like looking down a street. But into your phone’s screen.</p></blockquote></li>
      <li>Using the head-tracking capability, Amazon built Dynamic Perspective,
which allows a 3D image viewing experience in the phone. [<a href="#dynamic_perspective">Read more
below</a>]</li>
      <li>Fire and Prime
<blockquote><p>Amazon has built this phone for the Prime subscriber. Much like with the Fire TV, the Fire Phone will ship with a person’s Prime information already entered. The phone is, after all, all about selling more wares and Amazon is ensuring there are no barriers to entry for its best customers, those who subscribe to Prime. It also includes the personalized customer support service Mayday that debuted on the Kindle Fire.</p></blockquote></li>
      <li>Fire phone comes preloaed with a feature called ‘Firefly’ (<a href="#firefly">read about it
below</a>).</li>
      <li>13MP campera. The quality of the photos compares with those from Samsung
Galaxy S5 and iPhone 5S (<a href="#camera">Read more about the camera below</a>).</li>
      <li>Comes loaded with popular music streaming apps :
<a href="http://www.spotify.com/">Spotify</a> and
<a href="http://www.pandora.com/">Pandora</a>. Not restricted to Amazon Prime Music</li>
      <li>
        <p><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/18/amazons-mayday-service-on-fire-phone-means-it-might-be-able-to-sell-its-unique-new-features/">Mayday, which allows customers to interact with service agents over
phone or video chat in just one-tap, is also available on Fire Phone</a></p>
      </li>
      <li>Mayday would make it easier for customers to work with unfamiliar
features.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="dynamic_perspective"></a><strong><a href="http://www.cnet.com/news/amazon-fire-phone-dynamic-perspective/">Amazon Fire Phone’s Dynamic Perspective offers a new angle on smartphone
displays</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>
        <p>Amazon introduces a new way to experience a smartphone by using 3D
effects.
<blockquote><p>Instead of creating the illusion that an object is coming right for you, you’re given a, well, dynamic perspective on things. Look at a lockscreen picture of a forest, or egyptian ruins, and you’re given a chance to peer behind or around some of the objects on screen. For a more practical application, consider the maps: during the presentation, Amazon CEO Jeff Bezos tilted the phone to pan about the map, getting a better angle on details like a particular street’s name. Tilt the phone gently, and you’ll pull up Yelp info and reviews.</p></p><p>        <p>Or maybe you like shopping – in one example, Bezos pulls up a line of dresses on Amazon, and tilts the phone to scroll through the stack. Reading more to your liking? Just tilt the phone to scroll up and down a web page or e-book. You can even set things to autoscroll at a deliberate pace, essentially putting your literature on cruise control – drop a thumb to pause i</p></blockquote></p>
      </li>
      <li><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/18/amazon-phone-live-blog/#liveblog-entry-534596">Field of view of a single front-facing camera is too narrow to track 
user’s head</a></li>
      <li>Fire Phone uses 4 cameras mounted on the corners to track head and eyes.</li>
      <li>The company collected a lot of images of faces and applied machine 
learning to perfect the tracking capabilities.</li>
      <li><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/18/amazon-phone-live-blog/#liveblog-entry-534606">Dynamic Perspective SDK is available</a></li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="firefly"></a> <strong><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/18/amazons-fire-phone-introduces-firefly-a-feature-that-lets-you-identify-and-buy-things-you-see-the-real-world/">Fire phone introduces ‘Firefly’</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>A feature that lets you identify things that you see in the real world.</li>
      <li>
        <p>You can also directly buy off using this.
<blockquote><p>During the demonstration on stage, Amazon CEO Jeff Bezos showed off how Firefly can be used to scan barcodes on items, a book cover, a CD and more. There’s a Shazam-like audio recognition component as well – Firefly can identify songs, and it can even listen to a show, and then let you access that specific scene on Amazon, which is a clever trick.<br/>….<br/>Firefly can also recognize art, and then pull up the associated Wikpedia entry, something Apple’s Siri and Google Now can’t yet do.</p></p><p>        <p>At launch, Firefly is capable of recognizing over 100 million items, said Bezos. That includes 245,000 movies and TV episodes, 160 live TV channels, 35 million songs and 70 million product</p></blockquote></p>
      </li>
      <li>There is a dedicated button on the phone (besides the volume rocker) for
Firefly!
<img src="/images/firefly_button.jpg" title="“Dedicated Firefly button”" ></li>
      <li>Firefly looks like an extension of Flow, Amazon’s visual-recognition
technology that used to reside in its own standalone mobile app.</li>
      <li>When pointed at a sign board, it can identify the number (using
image-to-text) and determine if a phone number doesn’t exist, or 
directly call/save the number on the sign board.</li>
      <li>Firefly SDK will also be available, including text, audio and image
recognizers, content databases and support for custom actions allowing
developers to bend Firefly to their own personal needs.</li>
      <li>MyFitnessPal created an app, using the SDK, to find the nutritional value
of food item seen through the camera.</li>
      <li>The ability to recognize objects/entities through the camera lens 
of a phone would significantly benefit Amazon as identification 
is the first step in the purchasing process.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="camera"></a><strong><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/18/the-cloud-is-key-to-the-amazon-fires-ambitious-plan-to-win-over-smartphone-photographers/">Fire phone’s camera and unlimited cloud storage, for free!</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>Amazon Fire Phone hosts a 13MP camera</li>
      <li>Side-by-side shots show that the images are comparable to those from
iPhone 5S and Samsung Galaxy S5. However, it’d be best to wait until more
reviews pour in or try out yourself before commenting on the camera
quality.</li>
      <li>There’s a dedicated camera button, allowing users to jump to camera
directly by clicking the button (without unlocking the phone or searching
for the app)</li>
      <li>One click opens the camera app, second takes a photo.</li>
      <li>Unlimited storage on Amazon Cloud Drive
<blockquote><p>Each Fire Phone comes with unlimited uploads and storage to Amazon Cloud Drive, for life, for free. There are no conditions on that offer, which makes it much more attractive than either the paid offering from Amazon (iCloud Photos) or Google’s Drive offerings, which also use paid tiers to limit how much you can upload at once.</p></blockquote></li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ol>

<p> 
 </p>

<hr />
<p><em>‘<a href="/techblog/categories/tech-news">Tech News</a>’ is a series of articles where I attempt to share and summarize
recent developments in technology (and the related industry) that interest,
amaze and/or excite me. These would attempt to cover topics ranging from impressive 
apps to Google’s latest acquisition to jaw-dropping updates from SpaceX or Tesla Motors
and much more.</em></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tech News: Slingshot, JS Cryptography, Dropbox, ...]]></title>
    <link href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/18/tech-news-slingshot/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-18T23:22:07+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/18/tech-news-slingshot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ol>
  <li><strong><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/17/facebook-slingshot/">Facebook’s Slingshot challenges SnapChat with ‘Reply to Unlock’</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>Facebook’s new app <a href="http://www.sling.me/">Slingshot</a> is being seen as a 
competitor to SnapChat. </li>
      <li>It lets you share photos and 15-second videos with users on Slingshot.</li>
      <li>
        <p>The content is meant to be ephemeral, much like SnapChat. </p>

        <p><blockquote><p>As for what happens to your content, once everyone you’ve slinged something to views it, Facebook says it will delete the photo or video from its servers. There is a seven-day delay in case it has to investigate abuse reports, but the team says the content is gone after that. Whether users trust Facebook to keep its word is up to them. Past privacy missteps might scare people, but Facebook is under close scrutiny from the FTC to abide by the privacy policies it puts forward.</p></blockquote></p>
      </li>
      <li>An important catch in the app is that you can’t view the content shared 
by the user until you reply to it. (‘Reply to Unlock’)</li>
      <li>This aims to increase reciprocation and make everyone a content generator.</li>
      <li>Slingshot was born out of a hackathon. The motivation can be summarized by 
<blockquote><p>“My brothers are really not technical in any way”, Slingshot inventor and four-year Facebook Product Designer Joey Flynn tells me. “I’d take a photo, upload it in iMessage, and send it to them. And I would just see “Seen”, or in a month I’d see them and they‘d say ‘that was a cool photo’. But hey, I want to see what you’re up to! There was this missing reciprocation” he explains. That was the spark for Slingshot.</p></blockquote></li>
      <li>This app was <a href="http://mashable.com/2014/06/09/slingshot-app/">earlier released on app stored by mistake</a></li>
      <li>Facebook had tried to buy off SnapChat, but <a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2013/11/13/us-facebook-snapchat-idUSBRE9AC11E20131113">SnapChat had rejected the $3 billion buyout offer</a></li>
    </ul>

    <iframe src="//player.vimeo.com/video/98214265" width="500" height="400" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong><a href="http://matasano.com/articles/javascript-cryptography/">Browser based javascript cryptography considered harmful</a></strong></p>

    <p>Some of the things pointed out in the article. <em>[Not being an expert in cryptography, I would recommend readers to read
   the original article to avoid any miscommunication]</em></p>

    <ul>
      <li>Code could be injected when in transit. Can use SSL/TLS to avoid that, but 
then, in most cases, you could simply avoid cryptography at 
user end.</li>
      <li>There’s no certainty of information being removed from memory.</li>
      <li>It is not possible to verify the code/environment to be exactly as it is 
required to be. </li>
      <li>Javascript lacks a Cryptographically Secure Pseudo-Random Number Generator (CSPRNG). </li>
      <li><a href="https://crypto.stanford.edu/sjcl/">Stanford Javascript Crypto library (SJCL)</a>
developed at Stanford is a great work, but still insecure.
<blockquote><p>The authors of SJCL themselves say, “Unfortunately, this is not as great as in desktop applications because it is not feasible to completely protect against code injection, malicious servers and side-channel attacks.” That last example is a killer: what they’re really saying is, “we don’t know enough about Javascript runtimes to know whether we can securely host cryptography on them”. Again, that’s painful-but-tolerable in a server-side application, where you can always call out to native code as a workaround. It’s death to a browser.</p></blockquote></li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><strong><a href="https://www.privacyinternational.org/press-releases/uk-intelligence-forced-to-reveal-secret-policy-for-mass-surveillance-of-residents">UK intelligence forced to reveal secret policy for mass surveillance of
residents’ Facebook and Google
use</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>Secret policy define UK residents’ communication on Facebook, Google, Twitter, etc.
as ‘external communication’ because they use platforms based in the US, even
if the communication is between two people in the UK.</li>
      <li>This grants the secret services to indiscriminately intercept communication
on these platforms.</li>
      <li>For an ‘internal communication’, a warrant would be required, however that 
is not the case with ‘external communication’.
<blockquote><p>The Government believes that, even when privacy violations happen, it is not an “active intrusion” because the analyst reading or listening to an individual’s communication will inevitably forget about it anyway.</p></blockquote></li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/16/dropbox-has-quietly-acquired-parastructure-a-big-data-startup-in-stealth/">Dropbox acquired Parastructure, a Big Data Startup</a></strong>
 -
 <blockquote><p>So what exactly is Parastructure? According to the company’s LinkedIn profile, and its (now-offline) home page, it builds “beautiful data analysis software powered by cutting-edge open source infrastructure.” Parastructure’s GitHub pages give some clues as to what that data-analysis software was tackling, with areas covering Spark for cluster computing; Phoenix, a SQL skin over HBase; CrunchBase; and so on</p></blockquote></p>

    <ul>
      <li>The acquisition was done quite stealthily.</li>
      <li>Probably, Dropbox requires the software and the team to analyze its data</li>
      <li>Parastructure was an enterprise oriented startup and its acquisition indicates 
Dropbox’s intention on strengthening their image as an enterprise product.</li>
      <li>Dropbox’s increased effort in <a href="https://www.dropbox.com/business">Dropbox for
Business</a> brings it in direct
competition with Box, which is currently leading as an enterprise
solution.</li>
      <li>Both the companies are quite aggressively acquiring companies. </li>
      <li>In fact, Parastructure was acquired on the same day as 
<a href="/techblog/2014/06/17/tech-news-about-qeexos-fingersense-wristify-loon/">Box acquired Streem</a></li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><strong><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/18/apple-adds-a-new-entry-level-imac-for-1099/">Apple adds a new entry level iMac for ~$1,100</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>1.4GHz dual-core Intel Core i5 processor, 8GB memory, 500GB HDD, Intel HD Graphics 5000 on board
 
 </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ol>

<hr />
<p><em>‘<a href="/techblog/categories/tech-news">Tech News</a>’ is a series of articles where I attempt to share and summarize
recent developments in technology (and the related industry) that interest,
amaze and/or excite me. These would attempt to cover topics ranging from impressive 
apps to Google’s latest acquisition to jaw-dropping updates from SpaceX or Tesla Motors
and much more.</em></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tech News: About Qeexo's Fingersense, Wristify, Loon, ...]]></title>
    <link href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/17/tech-news-about-qeexos-fingersense-wristify-loon/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-17T23:06:39+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/17/tech-news-about-qeexos-fingersense-wristify-loon</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ol>
  <li><strong><a href="http://www.wired.com/2014/06/qeexo">Qeexo, a startup, is trying to redefine how we use touchscreens</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>Since the unveiling of iPhone, 7 years ago, not much has changed in how 
we interact with touchscreens.</li>
      <li>
        <p>Qeexo has developed a touchscreen technology capable of detecting difference
between a fingertip, a knuckle, fingernail and a stylus.</p>

        <p><blockquote><p>Today, FingerSense uses the standard accelerometer in a mobile device to pick up on the vibration patterns different parts of the hand produce when they come in contact with a touchscreen. The FingerSense machine-learning engine understands what part of the finger is touching the screen and triggers a correlated action. For instance, tapping a block of text with your knuckle could trigger the copy and paste menu to appear. To select text, you’d simply drag your knuckle down the text,much like you would a desktop mouse.</p></blockquote>
<!--more--></p>
      </li>
      <li>However, to be able to make an impact, the startup would need to be able 
 to convince the giants like Apple and Samsung to not only change the way
 touchscreen works, but also agree upon standards to make sure the same 
 gesture has similar behavior across devices.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><strong><a href="http://www.wired.com/2013/10/an-ingenious-wristband-that-keeps-your-body-at-the-perfect-temperature-no-ac-required/">Wristify, a wristband that could make air conditioning obsolete</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>Being prototyped at MIT, <a href="http://wristifyme.com/">Writify</a>, is trying to provide 
 temperature control (the function of a thermostat) by deceiving our senses.</li>
      <li>It tries to exploit the idea that cooling or heating only a part of the
 body makes us think differently about how cold or hot we are. </li>
      <li>Not only can it make AC’s obsolete, but also allow personalized, dynamic
 climate control. So, two people in the same room can enjoy a personalized
 climate. </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><strong><a href="http://www.wired.com/2014/06/google-balloons-year-later">Google’s balloon project, a year later</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>
        <p>A year ago, Google <a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.in/2013/06/introducing-project-loon.html">announced the Loon project</a>. 
Its aims and ideas can be summarized by 
<blockquote><p>We believe that it might actually be possible to build a ring of balloons, flying around the globe on the stratospheric winds, that provides Internet access to the earth below.<br /></p></blockquote></p>
      </li>
      <li>Over the year, they have been able to demonstrate how the plan can succeed.</li>
      <li>While initially, the balloons only lasted only a few days, Google was able
to identify the causes of failure by extensive analysis. </li>
      <li>Small, undetectable leaks in the polymer skins that must withstand huge
atmospheric pressure were identified as the primary cause of failure.</li>
      <li>
        <p>“The Loon crew not only strengthened the fragile seams where leaks often
occurred but took fanatic care in handling the envelopes.”
<blockquote><p></p></p><p>        <p>Google also improved Loon flight times by dramatically upgrading the altitude control system, increasing the vertical range of the balloons so they can catch more favorable winds. (Its balloons “steer” their way around the world by placing themselves in wind currents headed in the right direction.) As a result, it’s not unusual for Google to keep balloons flying for 75 days. One craft, dubbed Ibis 152 (Google uses bird species to nickname its balloons), has been aloft over 100 daysand is still flying. An earlier balloon, Ibis 162, circled the globe three times before descending. (It completed one circumnavigation in 22 days, a world record.) </p></p><p>        <p></p></blockquote></p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>Since the balloons had to stay in flight for long, Google couldn’t just rely
 on the data from National Oceanic Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), which
 supplied forecast for only 16 days. Google uses a giant database of weather 
 data to predict weather and wind conditions to be able to plot the optimal
 path (maximize battery life and avoid bad weather).</p>
      </li>
      <li>Loon can now also send data using LTE spectrum.
        <ul>
          <li>This boost the capacity of connections.</li>
          <li>Provides a reason for telecommunication companies to partner with them
to help provide signal in dead spots even in urban areas.</li>
        </ul>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>Google had recently <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/04/14/google-acquires-titan-aerospace-the-drone-company-pursued-by-facebook/">acquired Titan Aerospace</a>,
which makes high-altitude, solar powered drones.</p>
      </li>
      <li>By the next year, they expect to be able to provide service in certain
areas/countries.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><strong><a href="http://blogs.technet.com/b/microsoft_blog/archive/2014/06/16/microsoft-azure-machine-learning-combines-power-of-comprehensive-machine-learning-with-benefits-of-cloud.aspx">Microsoft Azure ML as a service</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>
        <p>Microsoft is using its experience in Machine Learning and its own cloud platform, 
Azure, to provide a platform for building ‘predictive analytics solutions’</p>

        <p><blockquote><p>Microsoft Azure Machine Learning, a fully-managed cloud service for building predictive analytics solutions, helps overcome the challenges most businesses have in deploying and using machine learning. How? By delivering a comprehensive machine learning service that has all the benefits of the cloud. In mere hours, with Azure ML, customers and partners can build data-driven applications to predict, forecast and change future outcomes – a process that previously took weeks and months.</p></blockquote></p>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><strong><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/16/box-acquires-yc-backed-streem/">Box acquires Streem</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>Streem is a company that allows customers to stream files to their desktops.</li>
      <li>From the description, it appears that the streaming experience was as if the file was present locally.</li>
      <li>It had <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/04/25/streem-seed-funding/">raised $875m in funding
recently</a> and was
backed by <a href="http://www.ycombinator.com/">YCombinator</a> </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ol>

<p> 
 </p>

<hr />
<p><em>‘Tech News’ is a series of articles where I attempt to share and summarize
recent developments in technology (and the related industry) that interest,
amaze and/or excite me. These would attempt to cover topics ranging from impressive 
apps to Google’s latest acquisition to jaw-dropping updates from SpaceX or Tesla Motors
and much more.</em></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
