<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: google | sudo random]]></title>
  <link href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/categories/google/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-12-29T10:04:01+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://rajatkhanduja.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Rajat Khanduja]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tech News: Cruise, Baarzo, Google Domains, ...]]></title>
    <link href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/24/tech-news-cruise-baarzo-google-domains/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-24T22:30:30+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/24/tech-news-cruise-baarzo-google-domains</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ol>
  <li><a href="/techblog/2014/06/24/tech-news-cruise-baarzo-google-domains/#cruise">For $10,000, your car can drive itself</a></li>
  <li><a href="/techblog/2014/06/24/tech-news-cruise-baarzo-google-domains/#laser-space">Laser message from space</a></li>
  <li><a href="/techblog/2014/06/24/tech-news-cruise-baarzo-google-domains/#google-domains">Google Domains (invite-only beta)</a></li>
  <li><a href="/techblog/2014/06/24/tech-news-cruise-baarzo-google-domains/#google-baarzo">Google may buy video search startup Baarzo</a></li>
  <li><a href="/techblog/2014/06/24/tech-news-cruise-baarzo-google-domains/#plaintext-passwd">Plaintext password offenders</a></li>
  <li><a href="/techblog/2014/06/24/tech-news-cruise-baarzo-google-domains/#lotus">Lotus: A complete webframework for Ruby</a></li>
  <li><a href="/techblog/2014/06/24/tech-news-cruise-baarzo-google-domains/#coders-high">Coder’s high</a></li>
  <li><a href="/techblog/2014/06/24/tech-news-cruise-baarzo-google-domains/#biggest-problems">We have the potential to solve the biggest problems of today</a>
<!--more--></li>
</ol>

<p> 
 </p>

<hr />

<ol>
  <li><a name="cruise"></a><strong><a href="http://www.theverge.com/2014/6/23/5834604/cruise-trying-to-reinvent-cruise-control-to-steer-brake-and-actually-drive-you">For $10,000, your car can drive
itself</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>Y combinator startup, Cruise Automation, has developed
<a href="http://www.getcruise.com/">Cruise</a>, an auto-pilot for your car.</li>
      <li>It is not really a ‘self-driving’ car yet.  <blockquote><p>It’s<br/>designed as a computer-controlled driving system that can take over when<br/>you’re behind the wheel. Turn it on like typical cruise control and it<br/>will keep the car going, but the added smarts will steer, brake, and<br/>avoid objects.</p></blockquote></li>
      <li>Not meant to replace the driver and can’t drive independently from point
A to point B. However, it can steer through stretches of road, managing
lanes and avoiding obstacles.</li>
      <li>Quite cheap compared to the ‘fully-self-driving’ options. </li>
      <li>RP-1, a $10,000 <em>kit</em>, currently compatible with two Audi models, can be
installed in the car to let it ‘cruise’ intelligently.</li>
      <li>Grander plan of the company is to collect freeway data that is shared
between vehicles
and is constantly updated between them.</li>
      <li>The technology is still in its early stages.</li>
      <li>
        <p>With Cruise, they can capture road images, GPS and inertial measurements
as well. </p>

        <p><blockquote><p>The goal is to create white-listed areas of freeways where the system knows its way and Cruise can be enabled.</p></blockquote></p>
      </li>
      <li>CEO, Kyle Vogt 
        <ul>
          <li>cofounded <a href="http://www.justin.tv/">Justin.tv</a>, which allows anyone to
broadcast video online.</li>
          <li>cofounded <a href="http://www.twitch.tv/">Twitch</a>, a live streaming video platform 
focused on e-sports and video-gaming.</li>
        </ul>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="laser-space"></a><strong><a href="http://science.nasa.gov/science-news/science-at-nasa/2014/18jun_opals/">Laser message from space</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>OPALS (Optical Payload for Lasercomm Science) provides a new method 
of data communication at extremely high speeds.</li>
      <li>
        <p>As reported by <a href="http://gizmodo.com/nasa-used-a-space-laser-to-download-video-from-orbit-at-1587523627">Gizmodo</a> earlier, on 5th June when ISS passed 
over Table Mountain Observatory in Wrightwood, California, it beamed 
a video for researchers waiting below.</p>

        <p><blockquote><p>… the laser rig beamed down the “Hello, World” video shown below in a mere 3.5 seconds, a feat that would have taken more than 10 minutes using traditional radio frequencies currently used for data transmission to outer space.</p></blockquote></p>
      </li>
      <li>OPALS was launched to the space station on board a <a href="http://www.spacex.com/dragon">SpaceX Dragon spacecraft</a>
in the spring of 2014</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="google-domains"></a><strong><a href="http://www.theverge.com/2014/6/23/5835560/google-launches-domain-registration-service">Google Domains (invite-only beta)</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li><a href="http://domains.google.com/about/">Google Domains</a>, still in beta, offers 
a domain registry service, competing against the likes of <a href="http://godaddy.com/">GoDaddy</a>
and <a href="http://www.bigrock.in/">BigRock</a>.</li>
      <li>For hosting, however, they have partnered with Squarespace, Wix, Weebly, and Shopify</li>
      <li>
        <p>The benefits?</p>

        <p><blockquote><p>First, it’s promising not to charge users anything extra to conceal personal information (e.g. name and address) that must be provided when registering a URL. Google Domains users can create up to 100 email aliases using their domain, and Mountain View also says it’s making domain forwarding super easy in case there’s already a Tumblr or existing site you’d like your new URL to point to. And you shouldn’t run into any problems or downtime (at least on Google’s end). Google Domains use the same DNS servers as Google’s other websites, ensuring “your domain will connect quickly and reliably to your website.”</p></p><p>        <p>Lastly, there’s the benefit of real customer support. Google says phone and email support will be available Monday through Friday from 9AM to 9PM EST</p></blockquote></p>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="google-baarzo"></a><strong><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/21/google-buying-baarzo/">Google may buy video search startup Baarzo</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>Baarzo’s technology description:
<blockquote><p>Unlike Google or YouTube searches, which only evaluate the text around the video, the Baarzo search technology actually analyzes the video content, recognizing hundreds of thousands of objects and millions of faces, and locates the precise moment in the video when the search objects interact in the way you had specified.</p></blockquote></li>
      <li>
        <p>Although the acquisition details are not yet public and even the acquisition
isn’t confirmed, TechCrunch received information from Facebook posts, 
including those by <a href="https://www.facebook.com/IITG.Alumni/posts/672681839483630">IIT Guwahati Alumni Association page</a>.</p>

        <p><img src="https://tctechcrunch2011.files.wordpress.com/2014/06/baarzo-facebook-screenshot.jpg?w=501&amp;h=508" title="“Post by IIT Guwahati Alumni Association page [source: TechCrunch]”" ></p>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="plaintext-passwd"></a><strong><a href="http://plaintextoffenders.com/">Plaintext password offenders</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>Storing passwords in plaintext is known to be an insecure way of dealing
with passwords, however, still
<a href="http://techland.time.com/2011/06/02/new-sony-hack-claims-one-million-user-passwords/">several</a>
<a href="http://blog.codinghorror.com/the-dirty-truth-about-web-passwords/">popular</a>
<a href="http://www.theregister.co.uk/2011/06/08/password_re_use_survey/">websites</a>
follow this archaic practice.</li>
      <li>This site tries to make a list of all such <em>offenders</em>. </li>
      <li><a href="https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Password_Storage_Cheat_Sheet">Here’s a quick password storage
cheatsheet</a>
(read about the topics discussed here in more detail to be sure of what
you are doing)</li>
      <li>And here’s an interesting Coding horror blog : <a href="http://blog.codinghorror.com/youre-probably-storing-passwords-incorrectly/">You’re probably storing
passwords
incorrectly</a></li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="lotus"></a><strong><a href="http://lotusrb.org/">Lotus: A complete webframework for Ruby</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>
        <p>From its author’s blog : 
<blockquote><p>It’s a complete web framework, with a strong emphasis on object oriented design and testability. If you use Lotus, you employ less DSLs and more objects, zero monkey-patching, separation of concerns between MVC layers. Each library is designed to be small (under 500LOCs), fast and testable.<br/>…<br/>We have infinite combinations. Small components have enormous advantadges in terms of reusability.</p></p><p>        <p>The power of these frameworks is combined together in Lotus applications.</p></blockquote></p>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="coders-high"></a><strong><a href="http://www.slate.com/articles/technology/technology/2014/06/coder_s_high_the_intense_feeling_of_absorption_exclusive_to_programmers.html">Coder’s high</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>An interesting reflection on the ‘intense feeling of absorption’
experienced while programming.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="biggest-problems"></a><strong><a href="http://www.christophmccann.com/blog/2014/6/23/we-have-the-potential-to-solve-the-biggest-problems-of-today">We have the potential to solve the biggest problems of today</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>This article takes a dig at the apps like <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/18/yo-yo/">Yo</a>.</li>
      <li>Yo, which recently got a $1.2 million in funding, has been raising
doubts and questions in its utility and worth.</li>
      <li>Used to send just two letters, ‘Yo’, the app has 50,000 active users 
who have sent 4 million “Yo’s” across.</li>
      <li>The article discusses that we should be focusing on more important issues
and how making another instant messaging app is not going to tackle 
the major issues of the world.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ol>

<p> 
 </p>

<hr />
<p><em>‘<a href="/techblog/categories/tech-news">Tech News</a>’ is a series of articles where I attempt to share and summarize
recent developments in technology (and the related industry) that interest,
amaze and/or excite me. These would attempt to cover topics ranging from impressive 
apps to Google’s latest acquisition to jaw-dropping updates from SpaceX or Tesla Motors
and much more.</em></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tech News: Wearable computing, Cgrep, Web Starter Kit, ... ]]></title>
    <link href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/21/tech-news-wearable-computing-cgrep-web-starter-kit/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-21T23:30:20+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/21/tech-news-wearable-computing-cgrep-web-starter-kit</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ol>
  <li><a href="/techblog/2014/06/21/tech-news-wearable-computing-cgrep-web-starter-kit/#passive-haptic-learning">Using Wearable Computers for Passive Haptic Learning and Rehabilitation</a></li>
  <li><a href="/techblog/2014/06/21/tech-news-wearable-computing-cgrep-web-starter-kit/#cgrep">Cgrep: a context-aware grep for source codes</a></li>
  <li><a href="/techblog/2014/06/21/tech-news-wearable-computing-cgrep-web-starter-kit/#nest-dropcam">Google backed Nest acquires Dropcam</a></li>
  <li><a href="/techblog/2014/06/21/tech-news-wearable-computing-cgrep-web-starter-kit/#google-block-sites">B.C. court ruling orders Google to block sites worldwide</a></li>
  <li><a href="/techblog/2014/06/21/tech-news-wearable-computing-cgrep-web-starter-kit/#google-web-starter-kit">Google launches starter kit for a more consistent web</a></li>
</ol>

<p>External links (not summarized below):</p>

<ol>
  <li><a href="https://blog.ethereum.org/2014/06/19/mining/">Discussion on possible solution of the GHash problem in Bitcoin network</a> 
 (would try to summarize this in a later post)</li>
  <li><a href="https://medium.com/the-physics-arxiv-blog/quantum-experiment-shows-how-time-emerges-from-entanglement-d5d3dc850933">Quantum Experiment Shows How Time ‘Emerges’ from Entanglement</a></li>
</ol>

<!--more-->

<p> 
 </p>

<hr />

<ol>
  <li><a name="passive-haptic-learning"></a><a href="https://plus.google.com/+ResearchatGoogle/posts/EgtfWJME37g">Using Wearable Computers for Passive Haptic Learning and Rehabilitation</a>
    <ul>
      <li>At Georgia Institute of Technology, a wireless glove, Mobile Music Touch (MMT),
has been developed that enables users to learn to play piano melodies while 
performing everyday tasks. </li>
      <li>The process is called ‘Passive Haptic Learning’.
<blockquote><p>Vibration motors are embedded in the glove at the base of each finger and the thumb.  The song being learned can be loaded onto a user’s mobile phone and is played as they go about their business.  As each note is played, the glove taps the finger corresponding to the appropriate key on a piano keyboard.  The result: in as little as 30 minutes, the user learns the “muscle memory” of the first phrases of the song, even if their attention has been devoted to another task.</p></blockquote></li>
      <li>
        <p>Even when distracted while the MMT tapped their fingers by tasks, like reading
emails, taking a graduate entrance exam and watching a movie, the subjects
were able to learn to play the songs.</p>

        <p><blockquote><p>Surprisingly, only the vibration was needed for the glove to be effective– on average, participants who only “felt” the music performed as well as those who heard the audio concurrently.</p></blockquote></p>
      </li>
      <li>Experiments suggest that it can also use in rehabilitation to help those
with paralysis because of spinal injuries.</li>
    </ul>

    <iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/Zi6t89pi17c" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
  </li>
  <li><a name="cgrep"></a><a href="http://awgn.github.io/cgrep/">Cgrep: a context-aware grep for source codes</a>
    <ul>
      <li>Grep tool for large code repositories</li>
      <li>Searches beyond simple pattern matching
        <ul>
          <li>Allows search in comments or code (except comment)</li>
          <li>Allows searching in string literals</li>
        </ul>
      </li>
      <li>Claims to have semantic search capability</li>
      <li><a href="http://beyondgrep.com/why-ack/">Ack</a> is another tool relevant for 
grepping through source code. Doesn’t have any semantic search capability</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="nest-dropcam"></a><a href="https://nest.com/blog/2014/06/20/the-nest-family-is-growing/">Google backed Nest acquires Dropcam</a>
    <ul>
      <li>Dropcam provides wifi connected camera setup to allow its customers to install
in their houses, so that they can check in on their home, irrespective 
of where they are in the world.</li>
      <li>Dropcam can be used to keep tabs on doors, windows or valuables at home. 
Even useful as a child monitoring tool.</li>
      <li>Nest, the company that creates intelligent thermostats, was acquired 
by Google recently. </li>
      <li>Like Nest’s acquisition by Google, this raises some privacy concerns. </li>
      <li>Probably to stave off thoughts like, “Now Google gets a video feed in 
my house!”, Nest explains in it’s blogpost that
<blockquote><p>Once the deal closes, we’ll incorporate Dropcam into how we do business at Nest. That includes how we handle everything from customer support to customer privacy. Like Nest customer data, Dropcam will come under Nest’s privacy policy, which explains that data won’t be shared with anyone (including Google) without a customer’s permission. Nest has a paid-for business model and ads are not part of our strategy. In acquiring Dropcam, we’ll apply that same policy to Dropcam too.</p></blockquote></li>
      <li>The numbers are not stated on their blogpost, but sources like <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/20/google-and-nest-acquire-dropcam-for-555-million/">techrunch</a>
quote a figure of $555m for the acquisition.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="google-block-sites"></a><a href="http://www.theglobeandmail.com/report-on-business/industry-news/the-law-page/bc-court-seeking-global-reach-orders-google-to-block-sites/article19212708/">B.C. court ruling orders Google to block sites worldwide</a>
    <ul>
      <li>A British Columbia court ordered Google (temporary injunction) to block
certain websites from ‘worldwide search engine’</li>
      <li>This raises the question of how much control can a country’s court exert 
on the Internet.</li>
      <li>The case in discussion involves a company whose trade secrets were stollen 
to create a competing product, which is being sold through a network 
of websites despite several court orders.</li>
      <li>While current procedures allow Google to block search results within 
Canada, since most sales occur outside Canada, they have been asked to 
block the site across the entire system. </li>
      <li><blockquote><p>But University of Ottawa law professor Michael Geist slammed the recent Google decision in a blog post on Tuesday, warning that it could lead to other countries demanding Google censor content worldwide, putting free speech at risk. “While the court does not grapple with this possibility, what happens if a Russian court orders Google to remove gay and lesbian sites from its database? Or if Iran orders it remove Israeli sites from the database?”</p></blockquote></li>
      <li>Earlier, EU enforced Google to honor <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/05/30/right-to-be-forgotten-webform/">‘Right to be
forgotten’</a>
for its own citizens, which allows users to <a href="https://support.google.com/legal/contact/lr_eudpa?product=websearch#">request removal of
pages/information from Google’s indexes</a>.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><a name="google-web-starter-kit"></a><a href="http://readwrite.com/2014/06/19/google-launches-starter-kit-for-a-more-consistent-web">Google launches starter kit for a more consistent web</a>
    <ul>
      <li>With the different kind of devices, people expect the same website to 
behave differently depending on the device (touchscreen vs desktop, 
mobile vs tablet)</li>
      <li><a href="https://developers.google.com/web/starter-kit/">Web Starter Kit</a> 
provides a boilerplate for developers to get started with multi-device 
development. </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ol>

<p> 
 </p>

<hr />
<p><em>‘<a href="/techblog/categories/tech-news">Tech News</a>’ is a series of articles where I attempt to share and summarize
recent developments in technology (and the related industry) that interest,
amaze and/or excite me. These would attempt to cover topics ranging from impressive 
apps to Google’s latest acquisition to jaw-dropping updates from SpaceX or Tesla Motors
and much more.</em></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tech News: About Qeexo's Fingersense, Wristify, Loon, ...]]></title>
    <link href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/17/tech-news-about-qeexos-fingersense-wristify-loon/"/>
    <updated>2014-06-17T23:06:39+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/06/17/tech-news-about-qeexos-fingersense-wristify-loon</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ol>
  <li><strong><a href="http://www.wired.com/2014/06/qeexo">Qeexo, a startup, is trying to redefine how we use touchscreens</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>Since the unveiling of iPhone, 7 years ago, not much has changed in how 
we interact with touchscreens.</li>
      <li>
        <p>Qeexo has developed a touchscreen technology capable of detecting difference
between a fingertip, a knuckle, fingernail and a stylus.</p>

        <p><blockquote><p>Today, FingerSense uses the standard accelerometer in a mobile device to pick up on the vibration patterns different parts of the hand produce when they come in contact with a touchscreen. The FingerSense machine-learning engine understands what part of the finger is touching the screen and triggers a correlated action. For instance, tapping a block of text with your knuckle could trigger the copy and paste menu to appear. To select text, you’d simply drag your knuckle down the text,much like you would a desktop mouse.</p></blockquote>
<!--more--></p>
      </li>
      <li>However, to be able to make an impact, the startup would need to be able 
 to convince the giants like Apple and Samsung to not only change the way
 touchscreen works, but also agree upon standards to make sure the same 
 gesture has similar behavior across devices.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><strong><a href="http://www.wired.com/2013/10/an-ingenious-wristband-that-keeps-your-body-at-the-perfect-temperature-no-ac-required/">Wristify, a wristband that could make air conditioning obsolete</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>Being prototyped at MIT, <a href="http://wristifyme.com/">Writify</a>, is trying to provide 
 temperature control (the function of a thermostat) by deceiving our senses.</li>
      <li>It tries to exploit the idea that cooling or heating only a part of the
 body makes us think differently about how cold or hot we are. </li>
      <li>Not only can it make AC’s obsolete, but also allow personalized, dynamic
 climate control. So, two people in the same room can enjoy a personalized
 climate. </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><strong><a href="http://www.wired.com/2014/06/google-balloons-year-later">Google’s balloon project, a year later</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>
        <p>A year ago, Google <a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.in/2013/06/introducing-project-loon.html">announced the Loon project</a>. 
Its aims and ideas can be summarized by 
<blockquote><p>We believe that it might actually be possible to build a ring of balloons, flying around the globe on the stratospheric winds, that provides Internet access to the earth below.<br /></p></blockquote></p>
      </li>
      <li>Over the year, they have been able to demonstrate how the plan can succeed.</li>
      <li>While initially, the balloons only lasted only a few days, Google was able
to identify the causes of failure by extensive analysis. </li>
      <li>Small, undetectable leaks in the polymer skins that must withstand huge
atmospheric pressure were identified as the primary cause of failure.</li>
      <li>
        <p>“The Loon crew not only strengthened the fragile seams where leaks often
occurred but took fanatic care in handling the envelopes.”
<blockquote><p></p></p><p>        <p>Google also improved Loon flight times by dramatically upgrading the altitude control system, increasing the vertical range of the balloons so they can catch more favorable winds. (Its balloons “steer” their way around the world by placing themselves in wind currents headed in the right direction.) As a result, it’s not unusual for Google to keep balloons flying for 75 days. One craft, dubbed Ibis 152 (Google uses bird species to nickname its balloons), has been aloft over 100 daysand is still flying. An earlier balloon, Ibis 162, circled the globe three times before descending. (It completed one circumnavigation in 22 days, a world record.) </p></p><p>        <p></p></blockquote></p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>Since the balloons had to stay in flight for long, Google couldn’t just rely
 on the data from National Oceanic Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), which
 supplied forecast for only 16 days. Google uses a giant database of weather 
 data to predict weather and wind conditions to be able to plot the optimal
 path (maximize battery life and avoid bad weather).</p>
      </li>
      <li>Loon can now also send data using LTE spectrum.
        <ul>
          <li>This boost the capacity of connections.</li>
          <li>Provides a reason for telecommunication companies to partner with them
to help provide signal in dead spots even in urban areas.</li>
        </ul>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>Google had recently <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/04/14/google-acquires-titan-aerospace-the-drone-company-pursued-by-facebook/">acquired Titan Aerospace</a>,
which makes high-altitude, solar powered drones.</p>
      </li>
      <li>By the next year, they expect to be able to provide service in certain
areas/countries.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><strong><a href="http://blogs.technet.com/b/microsoft_blog/archive/2014/06/16/microsoft-azure-machine-learning-combines-power-of-comprehensive-machine-learning-with-benefits-of-cloud.aspx">Microsoft Azure ML as a service</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>
        <p>Microsoft is using its experience in Machine Learning and its own cloud platform, 
Azure, to provide a platform for building ‘predictive analytics solutions’</p>

        <p><blockquote><p>Microsoft Azure Machine Learning, a fully-managed cloud service for building predictive analytics solutions, helps overcome the challenges most businesses have in deploying and using machine learning. How? By delivering a comprehensive machine learning service that has all the benefits of the cloud. In mere hours, with Azure ML, customers and partners can build data-driven applications to predict, forecast and change future outcomes – a process that previously took weeks and months.</p></blockquote></p>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><strong><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/06/16/box-acquires-yc-backed-streem/">Box acquires Streem</a></strong>
    <ul>
      <li>Streem is a company that allows customers to stream files to their desktops.</li>
      <li>From the description, it appears that the streaming experience was as if the file was present locally.</li>
      <li>It had <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2014/04/25/streem-seed-funding/">raised $875m in funding
recently</a> and was
backed by <a href="http://www.ycombinator.com/">YCombinator</a> </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ol>

<p> 
 </p>

<hr />
<p><em>‘Tech News’ is a series of articles where I attempt to share and summarize
recent developments in technology (and the related industry) that interest,
amaze and/or excite me. These would attempt to cover topics ranging from impressive 
apps to Google’s latest acquisition to jaw-dropping updates from SpaceX or Tesla Motors
and much more.</em></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
