<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: octopress | sudo random]]></title>
  <link href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/categories/octopress/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-06-30T02:14:25+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://rajatkhanduja.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Rajat Khanduja]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Octopress?]]></title>
    <link href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/03/11/all-set-and-ready-to-go/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-11T23:00:37+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/03/11/all-set-and-ready-to-go</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Finally, the site is up and ready! Now, all that remains is for me to make all 
this effort worthwhile and start blogging regularly. </p>

<p>The experience of setting up this blog, however, taught me a lot of things. Not 
just the lessons required to setup <a href="http://octopress.org">Octopress</a> or this
particular theme (<a href="https://github.com/shashankmehta/greyshade/">Greyshade</a>) or 
the DNS, but …. oh, who am I kidding, that’s the set of things I gained out of 
this entire experience. But they are not really worth sharing, except probably
the incident where I ended up with an infinite loop of URL redirection because
of an error in configuring the DNS! </p>

<p>So, this post will be less about the hows, but whys! Why did I choose Octopress
(and Greyshade) and why do I expect this to be a good choice? That’s the question
I will focus on. </p>

<!--more-->

<ol>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Blogging right from my editor</strong></p>

    <p>While this might not make much sense to a lot of people, it means a lot to 
some of us to be able to do most of the things from within our favorite editor.
Being a <a href="http://vim.org">vim</a> fan myself, it gives me immense pleasure to be 
able to write this blog from the editor. The fools who’d argue that one could
just copy the content from one’s editor for blogging doesn’t know the importance
of formatting, hyperlinking, etc. in blogging. It becomes all the more important
when you aim to write blogs that would tend to include code snippets. Like
Latex, I could write most of the content first and worry about the
formatting later. That brings me to the next point …</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Not having to worry about formatting</strong></p>

    <p>I quite perfectly fit the stereotype of developers who lack any sense about
the UI/UX. Many a times <a href="http://vickychijwani.github.io">Vicky</a> has laughed
off at the interface I found ‘usable’. In such a case, it only makes it harder
for me to imagine how the out put of my blog should look like. What Octopress
(or most such tools) offer, like Latex, is that most of the formatting 
decisions are taken care of without asking me. For instance, I needn’t worry
about the size of the heading or the color of the &lt;a&gt; tags. Should
it look green on hover or yellow? I needn’t worry about that. While at the same 
time, I get the ability to tinker parts that I do need fixed or changed. This
might be probably a good example of 
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Paradox_of_Choice%3A_Why_More_Is_Less">Paradox of Choice</a>. 
 I don’t have to think about making responsive UI, or the alignment of text
 or the margin-width, which saves me from making a lot of decisions and I 
 feel less tense! </p>

    <p>Having tried some platforms prior to this, I know that most platforms don’t
offer smooth writing/formatting tools. My experience with 
<a href="http://blogger.com">Blogger</a> was quite troublesome when I kept running into
issues with the blockquote tag and had to resolve it by looking into the
HTML itself. <a href="http://wordpress.org">Wordpress</a> and <a href="http://medium.com">Medium</a>
seemed to provide great formatting tools for general blogging, but none
that had good support for technical blogs right out of the box. Sure, there 
are plugins and being a geek I could have found them, but it only convinces
me that they were not made for technical content.</p>

    <p>Moreover, being a vim fan, I enjoy tools that focus on commands/instructions
based on ‘typed commands’ rather than key combinations. vim’s support
for markdown only makes it easier for me to be sure of getting what I expect.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Writing in offline mode</strong></p>

    <p>While this might be more of a perk that I expect to use over time, this is 
barely something I have required as of now. Since the setup doesn’t require
a special server to interpret the content, I can preview and/or save a draft
whenever I want. Only to deploy do I need access to the Internet. However,
as I am connected most of the time, this might not be as useful.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>Anyway, this is me just getting started with this platform and resuming blogging
after a long time. Maybe I’d have a lot of changes to these initial thoughts,
maybe not.</p>

<p>Cheers!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Migrating to Octopress]]></title>
    <link href="http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/03/10/migrating-to-octopress/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-10T07:51:16+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://rajatkhanduja.com/techblog/2014/03/10/migrating-to-octopress</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Now that I have a domain of my own and <a href="http://pages.github.com/">Github Pages</a>
are a good way to write and maintain a blog, I am trying to make a shift to
Octopress based blogging. While I maintain (if 8-13 months of inactivity counts
as maintaining) two blogs, <a href="http://blog.rajatkhanduja.com">Outlet</a> and 
<a href="http://techblog.rajatkhanduja.com">Technical Outlet</a>, I would be dropping the 
latter and shifting here. </p>

<p>At the time of writing this article, I do have certain projects that I would
like to write about. 
<!--more--></p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Integrating <a href="http://docspad.com">Docspad</a> with <a href="http://hasjob.co">HasJob</a></strong> </p>

    <p>More on this soon. Meanwhile, here’s the 
 <a href="https://github.com/hasgeek/hasjob/pull/81">pull request</a> for the same.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong><a href="https://github.com/Bookpad/docspad-sdk-python">Docspad Python SDK</a></strong> </p>

    <p>While working on the <a href="https://github.com/hasgeek/hasjob">HasJob code</a>, the
 need for such SDKs (more will follow) became clear. </p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong><a href="https://github.com/rajatkhanduja/WebComics">Android based Webcomics Reader</a></strong> </p>

    <p>As an avid Webcomics fan (my favorites being <a href="http://xkcd.com">XKCD</a> and
 <a href="http://smbc-comics.com">SMBC</a>, my first attempt at making an Android
 application revolves around the idea of making a single app for my favorite
 webcomics.  </p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong><a href="https://github.com/rajatkhanduja/ZeroKnowledgeDocuments/">Zero Knowledge Documents</a></strong></p>

    <p>While I have not made any improvements up on the basic tool in a long time,
 it has served my purpose well enough for now. </p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>But more on these topics later for now I have to go through the painful process
of setting up a blog. No offence to any of the developers or contributors of 
Octopress, but any such setup is painful, only the magnitude varies. It has
certainly been easy so far to get up and running, but there are several things
I’d want on the site. Let’s see how that goes about. Maybe, this could be the
subject of yet another post. </p>

<p>Here’s hoping for a better blogging future. </p>

<p>Cheers!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
